What's up, guys?
Are you enjoying the spin?
Hold on, I can actually make it faster.
Let me do this.
I'll make it so that it spins more every time you type something.
There.
Go nuts!
I may have put it too low, I don't know.
The small ones are spinning so fast you can't even see them, it's just a blur now.
Are you enjoying your Friday?
Isn't this a great idea for the waiting screen?
I was so proud of it.
Dude, I can barely see what you guys are writing, but then again, you're also spinning right now.
Hold on, someone said something.
You should add a counter?
For how many times the spin was triggered, then you can calculate how much energy we produced each stream.
Yo, that is actually kind of fun!
Maybe we have a little spinner during gameplay as well.
Like, maybe hidden, you know, but it's still counting.
And then at the end, how many households have you powered?
In Alaska?
Actually, a great suggestion.
How did you make it?
Just HTML.
And some Fable magic.
I'm not an HTML master.
I know a little, but...
I'm too lazy to...
...sit there and...
...write it all out in HTML.
Not sure if it's a good idea to encourage spam.
Yeah, I guess you're right.
But during breaks, I guess it makes sense.
That's kind of fun.
Maybe we can even make it so that...
...um...
...there's like a little power gauge...
...where you gotta reach the power gauge, you know, and then something happens.
That would be kind of cool.
The faster you spin it, and you gotta maintain it for a while to make that gauge hit that mark.
Right?
That could be cool.
I just had some...
...leftover Chinese food.
It was delicious.
It's always great the day after, actually.
Now I'm ready and powered up as well.
I've got the energy.
You have to power me up.
I mean, if you keep spinning...
...I will never run out of energy.
What did Jackie eat?
Same as always.
She has some dry food and some wet food.
And I always combine it.
In the beginning, I used to mix it up.
But she always somehow just eats the wet food first anyway.
So now I just put the wet food on top and she eats it all.
And then when she gets hungry later, she's like, ah, okay, fine.
I guess I have the dry stuff.
So she eats it.
Are you full-time now?
I am full-time.
I've been full-time for about one and a half years.
How much longer will your stream?
Um...
I don't know, probably like three hours or so.
Maybe a bit more.
It depends how...
How energetic I am.
You know?
I mean, it all depends on that.
But I actually planned it to go as far as 12 tonight.
So that would be...
Four and a half hours left.
But that was like the upper limit, right?
He hates create.
No, I actually love create.
I...
I like it more than I thought I would.
I've never been a big fan of mods in general, like, just across gaming.
It's just never really been a thing I was really interested in.
But this is actually really cool.
I like it.
Yeah, I kinda had low hopes.
But I'm satisfied.
This is...
This is good fun.
And it seems like I've barely scratched the surface as well.
Just based on all those achievements...
All the different tabs...
Like, I barely understand how to make a windmill work, right?
It's gonna be crazy...
Later on.
Dude, when I saw the belt...
And the little mechanical arm putting things on it...
That's when I knew, okay, okay, now we're talking.
Now we're talking.
Reminds me of Factorio.
Not that I played that a lot, but I played some and I loved it.
I loved stuff like that.
So this was the game you guys mentioned when you talked about Factorio-style Minecraft mods, right?
There wasn't, like, a different mod that was, like, specifically Factorio-related.
This is the one.
Okay, yeah, yeah, yeah.
Yeah, a Satisfactory experience.
Nice one.
But you're right.
It is actually kinda similar in that way.
I know what Satisfactory is, roughly.
Like, 3D Factorio.
I do wanna play Factorio someday.
They also have a whole new expansion to it.
Where you can go to space or something?
That sounds amazing.
Is that Dark Souls OST?
No, it's actually the Talos principle.
Yeah, it does feel good, Raffina.
It's, like, very native feeling.
Despite the...
Weird, uh, you know, breaking of rules in Minecraft.
Meaning, like, going diagonally.
And not just along the...
You know, the cardinal...
Directions.
The fact that you can make things more round.
And it's rotating.
At first, it was very weird to look at.
But now I'm getting a little used to it.
And it's kinda cool.
I mean, Max and Bunny...
It's been a while.
It's not been that long, though.
Right?
Like, when is that?
Like, two years?
And by the end of Season 1, I didn't really know everything either.
I had lots to do in Season 2.
When is the next stream?
Umm...
I don't know.
Probably in a couple days or so.
I'm kind of addicted to XCOM right now as well.
Alright, let's keep going.
I have things to make.
Oh, wait.
I need to do this.
There we are.
Okay.
Oh, it feels good, man.
Now I'm energized.
Got some food in me.
Jackie is...
What is she doing?
Yep.
She's on the couch now.
Falling asleep after eating.
Classic.
Just like me.
Except this time around, I'm making rotating contraptions.
Uh, I was rotating this over here.
Yeah, so I wanna do this.
Actually, wait.
A bit of dirt first.
Nope.
But I don't think, uh...
Yeah, okay.
Let's see.
Definitely faster.
Very nice.
Hey!
Not bad, eh?
Thanks.
Oh wait, there's one left.
Yo, I love that...
You know, I put it down right before it hit it.
And it still worked.
Stuff like that, man.
It's nice.
That's polish.
You know?
Okay, so we got a bunch of these now.
The reason I made these...
Is because I wanted to make this weird toolbox thingy.
This one.
So we have two golden sheets.
We need a...
Oh, I was about to say we need a trap chest, but we don't.
Leather we have.
We can definitely make a chest.
Yeah.
Anything else we needed?
Toolbox.
The cogwheel.
And they call it a little.
See what this is all about.
Woah.
What?
Ok.
Wait a second.
Are you saying...
Wait a minute...
Let's say I put...
This in here.
No.
Wait, why is it zero?
What's a good example here?
There's no way this works.
Maybe it is understood.
Hold on.
What does it say?
Nearby players can hold the toolbox keybind to access its contents.
Wait, what do you mean keybind?
It changes inventory contents?
Wait, what keybind?
Hold on.
Maybe there's like...
Configured...
Creative...
inventory?
Create simulated?
Toolbox...
Oh!
Alt!
Huh?
Oh, dude, this is insane!
Wait, what?
Okay, I can't open it while this is open.
I thought what it did was it allowed me to craft things with wood, even though it didn't have wood on me.
You know what I mean?
Like, I could access the materials for the crafting without being next to it.
But I guess it's smart that I can do this.
Oh.
Oh, actually, I can just tab it too.
Oh, not quite.
I just go down and release.
Oh, okay.
And then I click again to remove it.
Yo, that is actually kinda sick that I can do that.
And what if I have multiple items?
Wait, what happens to the items I have in my...
Oh, they just go in here?
Oh!
That is kinda cool.
Alright.
Definitely gotta get used to that.
And I gotta look at that keybind menu again.
In the future to really get an understanding.
Now, what on earth can I use a whisk for?
That's what I wanna know.
I do have a lot of iron.
And these.
Let's go smash.
Smash em.
Actually, not all of them.
Half.
Well, that's doing that.
Shoot.
Sure.
The pieces fit.
New recipe some...
Oh, that's a...
What even is that?
So, shoot to me sounds like...
similar to...
a hopper.
But let's see.
Transport items vertically from and to inventories.
Using the wrench, a window can be created.
Oh, that's actually kinda cool.
Using industrial iron blocks...
Wait, what does that say?
Using industrial iron blocks, shoots can be encased.
Okay.
Falls down.
But what is...
the difference?
Oh.
Whoa.
Okay.
Placing shoots targeting the side faces of another will make it diagonal.
That looks really cool.
Nice.
Transporting items upward.
Okay, now that sounds useful.
Ha!
You have a little wind machine?
Using encased fans at the top or bottom, a shoot can move items upward.
Inspecting...
Oh, hold on, I need to read that again.
Inspecting shoots with engineer's goggles reveals information about the movement direction.
What?
Some kind of hut?
On the blocked end, items will have to be inserted slash taken from the sides.
Oh my god, they're so...
This is like...
This system is so deep.
Smart shoots are vertical shoots with additional control.
Items in the filter slot specify...
Oh!
Ha!
This is a much...
easier version of what I was making manually in Minecraft.
Oh, look, you can even see a little preview!
Use the value panel to specify the extracted stack size as well?
Damn!
Alright.
Redstone power will prevent smart shoots from acting...
Yeah, arresting them.
Sick.
Shoot supremacy!
That's amazing.
Still though, um...
The wind machine.
Also called a windmill.
We did unlock a bunch of new stuff.
I just wanna see...
Okay, so it's like...
It almost looks like a little, um...
What do you call it?
Piston.
But it's not.
Let's see if we unlock something like that with all the new stuff we got.
This is the closest thing in visuals.
Auger shaft?
I guess that is something that connects shoots together?
That's what it looks like at least.
Steam engine sounds insane.
Here we go.
Portable storage interface!
Okay, that sounds insane.
No idea what it is, but it sounds amazing.
Storage...
Let's ponder on it.
What?!
Moving inventories can be tricky to access with automation!
Just...
Dude...
This component can interact with storage without the need to stop the contraption.
How?
Place a second one with a gap of one or two blocks in between.
Okay.
So they face each other.
Whenever they pass by each other, they will engage in a connection.
Ha!
Cue the docking scene from Interstellar.
Also, I'm an idiot.
Instead of trying to look for the item in my inventory, I can just go in here and try and see if I actually know it.
Why didn't I do that for the windmill?
While engaged, the stationary interface will represent all inventories on the contraption.
Item...
Oh, wait!
So if I put it down there, it goes there!
So they're like linked.
It's considered one inventory now.
Whoa!
Or extracted.
After no items have been exchanged for a while, the contraption will continue on its way.
Dude!
That looks so cool!
It looks like a little cannon almost.
You know, you put, uh...
I don't know, rocks in here and then it goes...
Blup!
I wonder if you can make something like that.
Redstone control.
Redstone power will prevent the stationary interface from engaging.
I figured that was what was gonna happen.
So just keep...
Dude, can you make cranes?
This looks like a crane almost!
What the hell?
What is this thing in the center?
We don't know, okay.
Yes, we do know!
This is the weird...
Uh... piston.
That I was trying to look for earlier.
I think.
Nah, it's not.
Nevermind.
I lied.
It's not.
Okay, very cool.
Let me actually see this one again.
Oh, that's... oh, just putting that in between, okay.
It's just to decorate.
It's just decoration on that one.
I wanna make a belt.
At some point.
Not right now.
Uh, let me quickly check the windmill thing.
Because now I can just do this.
So I don't know that one.
Got it.
Okay.
Good to know that I don't have to look for it.
But I can look for other things.
Let me go to the very last page.
Mechanical press.
Let's get a trap door.
Maybe that does something.
Yeah, look!
Wow!
Mega door.
Didn't do anything.
Let's do a...
Desk bell?
Ring for service.
Emits a redstone signal when activated.
Plays a sound when arriving at the target floor.
What?
Hold on.
Are you saying there's elevators?
Wait a second now.
Oh, that is delicious.
What a sound.
Oh, that's nice.
That's like the dinner bell.
Food is served!
I like it.
Let's eat some of these pork chops.
This is one of my favorite items so far.
I just love it so much.
Okay, what else do we have?
Oh yeah, this one.
Dude, I kind of want to try and couple some minecarts together now.
Let's make a symmetric sail as well.
Let's...
Wait, what?
Is this a plane?
When moving on a simulated contraption, regular sails provide lift?
No way.
What's that?
Some kind of engine.
Okay, but...
There's no way it looks this smooth in the game though, is it?
Lift is generated relative to the speed of the sail and is applied perpendicular to its surface.
Yeah.
That way.
Yes.
Airplane 101 here.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Unlike regular sails, symmetric sails only produce drag.
Oh, okay.
So this is good for steering.
That's why it's back there.
You can...
Do this.
Note that when moving a parallel...
Okay, yeah, you know what?
Let's not look at this.
We don't need this right now.
This is too much.
We don't need this.
It's way too much.
Let's just calm down and make a white tablecloth.
That's what I want to do.
Because if we have a dinner bell, we need to have a table to sit at and eat it.
Not the bell, but the food.
We have one bread we can celebrate.
Also...
Actually...
Give me a second.
Be right back.
I forgot to bring this.
We need the dinner bell.
We need a nice tablecloth, some spaghetti, and some wine.
Cheers, guys.
Happy Friday.
Oh, yes.
Oh, that's nice.
Oh, that's a good one, actually.
That's delicious.
Okay.
You know what?
I want more music.
Hello?
Give me music.
Can I make the music?
Give me fully music right now.
There was a way to do this, like...
In a way...
Oh, God.
Guys, how do I activate the music?
Hold on.
Music.
How do I activate the music?
Okay, that's...
Oh, I see.
It's a new option.
Damn.
I just want that Minecraft music.
That's fine.
I can have this.
That's good enough for me.
I wonder if I can crank it.
How would that even work?
It doesn't even make sense.
What if I hit it with different...
Oh.
Alright, alright.
Cool.
Uh...
Where was I?
We were making sales, and then I was making other things.
Here we go.
Item hatch.
Trap door and anticide alloy.
Quickly solves your inventory clutter and makes it someone else's problem.
That sounds like something for me.
Deposit your held item into the container and it's placed on.
Sneak click to deposit everything except hotbar.
Oh!
This is my favorite item?
Are you serious?
Wait, wait, wait, wait.
I guess it would have a...
It needed something to put it into.
I thought it would just be someone else's problem.
They lied.
It's suddenly my problem now.
What the hell?
I need a chest or something.
Give me...
Oh.
Did I use all my wood?
No, I didn't.
I'm gonna make a bit more plank.
Let's keep that.
Also, maybe I can ponder this.
I didn't pay attention.
No, I can't.
Also, it would show up in the top if I could.
And it didn't do that.
Okay, so now we do a chest.
Ah, wait a sec.
Maybe that needs to be...
here.
Okay, so now...
Let me read this again.
When R clicked to process your health item into the container, it is...
Sneak click.
Okay, okay, sneak click.
Oh wait, so the container, it is placed on?
When you say on, do you mean...
On top?
No, you mean like...
Oh, maybe this needs to be turned around?
Put it in the back?
Yo, this is one of my favorite things.
Ever!
This is incredible!
Ah, but then I can't grab it again, right.
So I would need to...
Sort it!
Ah!
I would need to sort it on the other side!
We're gonna make a sorter.
And I have a suspicion it's gonna be a lot easier.
Let's take it all back for now.
Haha, this is great!
I love that.
Very nice.
It also looks cool, you know?
Just fucking throw it away.
Throw it in there.
Get off of me.
Very nice.
Okay, what else?
Show me more.
Let's make an auger shaft.
Ponder on that shit.
Powered auger shafts...
We'll transport items and extract them from actors.
Like Tom Cruise?
Using a wrench you can cycle between the auger shaft and auger cog.
Okay.
What is...
But what is it?
Alright, it said we can steal from actors.
What is considered an actor?
Is this an actor?
It's making...
It's doing an act?
Speaking of wrench, I think we can make that.
Okay.
Using industrial iron blocks, auger shafts can be encased.
But what is the point of encasing?
Item flow can be observed via the indicator on the auger cog.
Oh.
Or by inspecting the auger while wearing goggles...
Dude, I want these goggles?!
These goggles that are being talked about here!
Items cannot be inserted or extracted from the auger cog.
Right.
But like...
I still don't understand the point...
Of this.
Is it just to transport items?
But there's so many other ways to do it.
Why would I do this?
Extracting from harvesting actors using the...
Oh, harvesting actors.
You mean like the plow?
Oh my god.
We gotta make this.
Iron sheets.
We got them.
Is it finished bonking?
Yo, I'm kinda worried about these just lying here.
They're not gonna despawn, right?
Cuz...
Minecraft...
Oh shit.
You know, Minecraft logic would dictate that it would.
But probably not.
Auger cogwheel.
So...
Oh my god, I can make this?
Okay, hold on, hold on!
Detour!
We gotta make the saw.
Upward facing mechanical saws can process a variety of items.
Okay.
I see it.
Oh my god!
Oh, it's making them...
Oh, the processed item always moves against the rotational input to the saw.
So we need a belt for this, or what?
Aha!
Saw can work in line with mechanical belt.
Yeah.
Figured.
What is that gonna do?
When an ingredient has multiple possible outcomes, the filler slot can specify it.
The filler slot?
I don't think I've seen the filler slot...
...yet.
But I would love to see it.
Also, do we know what this is?
Oh, that's the saw.
Right.
I was like...
I mean, the bottom part didn't look like the saw.
Shit.
Okay, so we put in stone.
Without filter, the saw would cycle through all outcomes instead.
Oh.
So it's like random?
Cutting trees with the mechanical saw!
I need to see this.
When given rotational force, the mechanical saw will cut trees directly in front of it.
Okay, but hold on!
Before I continue, why not just use the drill?
I'm gonna tell you why.
Because with this, it's gonna cut the bottom part, it's gonna collapse the rest.
Watch.
It's the only explanation.
Please let it be so.
Oh my god.
No.
In order to cut the tree fully, the saw has to break the last block connected...
Oh my god.
Please show that.
Show it to me.
Yes, it's happening.
Oh, that's amazing!
Dude.
I need a portable saw.
Also called a chainsaw.
Yo.
Can I do that?
Using mechanical saws on contraptions.
Whenever saws are moved as part of an animated contraption?
Yeah?
Go on!
They will cut any trees the contraption runs them into!
Okay, what is this?
We don't know what that is.
This thing right here is so important to figure out what is.
This has to be the main thing we try to figure out here.
It will cut any trees the contraption runs them into.
That is just amazing.
Dude, you can...
Yo.
We can mow down an entire forest.
With this.
We can control the planet.
We will dominate everything.
Inventories attached to the contraption will pick up their drops automatically.
What?!
Okay.
Yay!
That is crazy.
Wow.
Okay, this...
The saw...
Oh, shit.
Block...
Okay.
Right, so we can produce any one of these.
But we can use the filter thingy to choose which one.
Wait, what?!
One iron ingot becomes this?!
Hold up!
What do you mean?
Dude, watch this.
There's no way it's...
This could actually be super...
This may actually be worth...
Check this out!
Hold on.
No!
What are you doing?
No, no!
Stop!
Face the thing, you idiot!
There we go.
I just had an orgasm.
That is insane!
Guys, this will change everything.
I can make any house I want.
This guy's trying to steal my wood!
You hit a potato.
Wait!
Okay, dude, check it out!
What?!
I...
I plant saplings, right?
I make big tree.
I make big manisaw.
I spin manisaw.
Tree go...
Boom.
And I take tree, I repeat.
Oh my goodness.
I'm gonna explode the tree.
We have saplings, right?
Wait, now we need...
Now we need a way to figure out how to plant a sapling.
Automatically.
Uh...
I must have some kind of sapling.
Somewhere.
Oh, maybe not.
Okay, um...
That's fine.
The saw may be my favorite item so far.
Followed by the...
Item.
But yeah.
Wrench!
Wait, hold on.
No.
No!
Whenever harvesters are moved as part of an animated contraption...
Yeah?
And you can put a chest on it and collect it?
Dude, say no more!
I get it.
I'm starting to understand everything that's going on right here.
I understand.
Give me this.
Multi-purpose tool for working with your kinetic contraptions.
When used on blocks, rotates components around the clicked face.
Sneak while interacting to dismantle.
When used on contraptions, relocates assembled minecart and train...
Sorry.
Did you say train?
Alright.
Sign me the fuck up for that.
Whisk time!
Ah!
New recipes unlocked.
Where?
Which one?
Oh, probably this one?
Mechanical mixer.
Whoa.
I'm guessing fluids?
But why would you mix?
Wait.
Wait, wait, wait.
Oh, right.
Okay.
Wait.
Did I just break it forever?
Oops.
Oh no, it's here.
Okay.
Oh, thank god.
Alright.
Uh...
Okay.
There's no way I can crank this shit, right?
No way.
It needs to be moved.
Would love to crank it.
And again, I guess that wouldn't really help me much if I cranked that shit.
It's much easier to go around just clicking.
But let me see here.
I guess it needs to be attached to a block.
Like in that video.
What are these even?
They look like pistons a little bit.
This thing right here is able to rotate things.
This is also the thing that, I think at least, the windmill was on.
It's something that allows things to rotate.
Maybe we have it now.
No, we don't.
Because it would have showed us...
Ah, actually, hold on.
I'm an idiot.
These...
Whoops.
The ponder system will actually not...
Like, if this says question mark, it still could mean that I have it in my book here.
I just haven't made it.
I think.
I could be wrong on that.
Let me actually just go over here and put in some things.
Let me see the mixer.
I figured it would be that.
With a mixer and basin, some crafting recipes can be automated.
Two dyes go together.
When two dyes love each other very much.
You get...
Purple.
Available recipes include any shapeless crafting recipe plus a couple extra ones.
Oh.
Shapeless, meaning it doesn't matter which order you combine them.
That makes sense.
Some of those recipes may require the heat of a blaze burner.
Got it.
Okay.
Mixer...
How have I not made this yet?
I feel like this would be made of rubber.
The filter slot can be used in case two recipes are conflicting.
Yeah, yeah, okay.
So the whisk...
I guess it was just used to make that thing.
Wait, is that it?
Hold on.
Linear chassis.
That looks a lot like the thing.
That's it!
Linear chassis connect to identical chassis blocks next to them?
Okay.
Keep going.
Tell me.
When one is moved by a contraption, the others are dragged...
Say no more.
This may be it, finally.
Oh wait, no, no, no.
Actually, this one was more gray.
Uh...
Yeah.
Chances of different type or facing another direction will not attach.
This is the one for the harvester.
Yeah, okay.
But we still...
Oh, we still don't know what this...
This is the frickin' thing we're looking for.
I thought this was the thing we just got.
But it's actually that thing.
This is the subject of the scene.
Damn.
Too bad.
Weighted ejector.
Shooting things out?
Hmm.
Wait, redstone contact?
It's also new.
Propeller.
Propeller as in making a boat!
Or what?
Because I would love to do that.
Again, my inventory is getting filled to the brim here.
Dude, the saw and crank combo is...
You know what?
This is the ideal situation and place for that.
This is my toolbox.
This is what I bring with me.
Let's say I'm out and about, you know, and oh, I feel like cutting down some trees.
I can crank that shit.
Not bad.
Maybe the wrench goes in the toolbox.
Actually, I...
What was this again?
Rotating components around the clicked face.
So...
You're saying, for example, if there's a wheel?
Oh.
Wait.
Huh?
Around the clicked face.
If I click this face...
What?
Oh, I gotta hit this thing?
Okay.
What if I stand here?
Oh!
So, it's in the direction I'm facing.
So, if I stand here, it's gonna face the other way.
And if I want it back...
Aha.
Okay.
I think I understand.
Let me try this one then.
So, if I want this one to face that way...
Yeah.
Okay.
If I want it to face that way...
Ah!
What if I want it to go...
Flat?
Hmm.
What then?
Maybe from the top?
Eh.
How would I do that then?
From the top?
Oh.
Oops.
I right-click.
I didn't left-click.
I just love sitting next to this and listening to it.
Cheers.
Dude, that is one tasty-ass wine.
Holy shit.
Love spinning things.
Okay, I think, um...
Let me just...
Pulp!
Oh!
I can mix saplings with water and get...
Pulp.
We should do that.
I have declared it so.
Let's make some pulp.
Hold on, what do you use pulp for?
Uh, you use it to...
God, I don't even know.
Make paper?
Yeah!
Paper!
Right?
Reuse, uh...
Reusability.
No, what's the word?
When you reuse things?
What's the word for that?
Basin.
In fact, maybe we can use this thing that's already rotating.
Check it.
Huh?
Oh!
Okay, so you go like there.
I want you to filter doors through this basin for me.
Take it off, take it off.
I regret.
That's fine.
Then we're gonna...
Extend this with a shaft.
And then over there, we're gonna have a mixer.
My question now is though...
Is this gonna...
You know, be less powerful overall?
Because it's already, you know...
Extracting energy there?
Or is it just infinite energy?
We'll see, I guess.
But in this one, I needed...
What was it?
Water and some saplings.
Oh!
I got a bunch of saplings.
Now we just need some water.
And I do have a...
Little water carrier.
There.
Also called a bucket.
Also, let's do this.
Oh, nice little animation as well.
Oh, I probably have to do this.
Oh, wait a minute.
This is a cock wheel.
Oh!
Hold on.
I see the issue.
So that would mean...
How do we do this in the best way?
Oh!
Check it out.
We're gonna use...
A vertical gearbox.
And then...
We use a wheel!
Wheel, wheel, wheel...
I don't even have a wheel?
That's crazy.
Maybe a small one.
Maybe a big one.
Okay.
So the big wheel requires...
Oh, I can make it.
Good.
Let's try the small one first.
We can actually...
Wait, hold on.
Wait a second!
There's a way to get infinite speed here.
Now we do a small one.
Whoops.
Realistically, you cannot do this in real life, but...
I definitely wanna do it here.
Let's just make a...
Let's make a couple of these.
How about 10?
And then 10 of these.
We need more wheels.
Now we're gonna...
Let me see.
What's the best way to do this?
Can we just directly attach?
Oh!
Okay, well in that case...
Then we don't need the shaft.
Shaft.
Boink.
Then we do a small wheel.
I just assumed you couldn't get infinite energy like this.
Maybe there's an upper limit on this.
We'll see.
I'm gonna keep going until it tells me I can't.
Oh, was that it?
Ah, it's trying to connect there.
Of course.
Hehehehe.
Okay, okay, okay.
That's very fast.
Small one.
A little finicky here.
There we go.
Woo!
Damn, son!
Whoa!
What the fuck?
This is not how wheels work in real life, kids.
Oh!
There's gotta be an upper limit to this.
Hahaha!
Okay, wait, wait, wait.
Let's...
Wait, wait, hold on.
Give me a shaft.
Shaft me.
And now...
Wait, how...
What is this gonna look like?
That's my question.
Oh, wait, something's wrong.
Overstressed!
Okay, I see.
It appears that this contraption is overstressed.
Add more sources or slow down the components with a high-stress impact.
Fine.
All right.
Let's see what the limit is.
Oh, okay.
This one should work, I think.
No!
Well, okay.
Fine.
Okay, you know what?
I'm happy with it being here anyway.
This is a good spot for it.
In fact, we don't really need this, do we?
Let's put that there.
And then we put the...
Ah, but then again.
Having it all at one height is kinda nice.
I do like that.
There we go.
We put this guy there.
And then the little guy below.
Where is it?
Nice.
And then we continue this.
Gonna put a big wheel.
Put this one over there.
I think this was already considered too much.
Let's see.
Is this considered too much?
Okay, that's fine.
Good to know.
Then make one here.
Wait, obviously.
Actually, we don't even need that.
The thing is that I kinda...
I wanna keep it at the same height though.
That's the annoying thing right now.
Ah, but wait a second.
On this one we need to have a horizontal spin, right?
That was the whole point.
Oh no, stop, stop.
How can I...
No, I need to sort of...
Wait, how did I do this before?
Maybe you kind of...
Yeah.
There we go.
Well, now it's too low.
Ah, I don't know how I wanna set this up.
I wanna make it a little more elegant though.
This is the thing.
Hmm.
So before I had two shafts, which...
Ah, wait, wait, wait.
Can I actually just connect it directly?
Ah, no, of course not.
Because we need a wheel there.
I could also just use this, uh, gearbox.
But what's the difference between that?
Ahhhh...
It would be a vertical one.
But I wanna make it go faster, right?
So that's the whole point of having it...
down here instead.
Where do I want it though?
I gotta get used to this weird arrow system.
It's confusing me a lot.
Now I wanna make it...
here.
And then we turn it 90 degrees.
There's really no easier way to do this.
And now it's at the...
correct height, at least.
But now it's offset.
That's gotta be an easier way to keep things aligned, I imagine.
That's definitely gonna work.
Now we put this...
And now it's going way faster.
Basin?
Oh, I lost the water, didn't I?
It seems very inefficient.
Oh no, you bastard!
Oh, wait, it needs to be smaller, I think.
We can't do it this way.
Wait, what?
Hold on.
I'm not getting this, at all.
If I put a big wheel now...
Let's say I don't care about where it is.
Nah, that's not gonna work either.
Shit!
Vertical.
Is that really the only way?
I mean, so now it's spinning.
It appears that this mechanical mixer is not rotating with enough speed.
Okay.
Got it.
So basically what you're saying is...
And then we take a small wheel.
Yeah.
I'm not good at doing this.
Ha ha ha ha ha ha!
Fuck!
This is some ugly shit.
But hey, at least it's kinda cool to look at.
I like the spinny spin.
We finally got it spinning!
Ha ha ha ha ha!
Oh, shit.
Okay.
How about we just redo this?
First of all, we don't even need this shit.
Ha ha ha ha!
The gearbox is useless there.
We don't need that!
What else can we get rid of?
Let's...
So now we've over-complexified it.
Let's try and simplify.
This is fine.
So right now...
We're spinning this thing.
This is all forgotten.
We have a big wheel coming out here.
And...
We have a...
90 degree wheel there.
So that we can have a small one.
So that we can have this one.
Because I don't think you can connect a big wheel to the small one here.
Right?
Wait, maybe you can.
Oops.
That's also the wrong item.
Yeah, it's not gonna spin.
So the only way to connect to it is via this little gear.
Okay.
But I want it one higher, right?
So maybe I put the big wheel one higher here.
Like that.
But then we're gonna be one higher.
Fuck!
Huh.
Actually, wait, wait, wait.
There is one thing.
No, there's not.
There's not a thing.
Sideways!
Well, that's not gonna do much.
Maybe I cannot do what I'm trying to do.
Basically, what I'm trying to do is to have my spinny spin on the same line at the same height.
You know?
While getting more speed every time.
Maybe there's no need to be doing this.
I could also go off in a different direction here, right?
What I could do...
Is to take a small wheel...
And put it there.
And then we already have a thing we can connect to.
That's much smarter.
Except it's too slow?
Not enough speed.
Okay.
Oh, it's also...
Oh, it's connected to that one.
Which is the first one.
Wait, are we actually slowing things down?
Is this thing slower than usual?
No.
It's the same.
Put this here.
And then we need a big one.
It doesn't fit.
It doesn't...
It does fit!
A little...
Ah, okay.
It works.
But now it's too low again.
Oh!
Poof!
Put it on the other side then.
Man, this is a...
This is breaking my brain, dude.
This is why I'm not a mechanical engineer.
I'm not dealing with this shit.
I just do it on paper instead.
Much easier.
Uh...
How do I do this, man?
Like, I could do it, but I don't want to do it in an ugly way.
I'm trying to do it nice.
Oh, wait a minute.
Maybe belts could be used...
Here.
Instead of just using these, but I don't have any belts, right?
Or I just accept that we're gonna be at different heights.
Maybe that's the solution.
Oh, what am I doing?
I need a big wheel.
That's not a big wheel.
Small wheel.
Hey, wait!
Oh!
Ah!
Wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait!
I get it now, I get it.
Here?
It's because I couldn't connect to this before.
Now we put this down here, and now we're at the same height!
Ah, there it is.
That's the trick.
Oh, wait.
Hold on.
Now we gotta translate this into...
This motion...
So that would be...
Actually, we don't even need this.
This is still fast.
Wait, I don't even need this?!
I do need that.
Hold on a minute.
I just had an idea.
If I put a big wheel here...
And a small wheel...
No, a big wheel again, but...
There.
We're almost there!
It's almost right!
In an elegant way.
Actually, we are there!
We are there!
Now we put in the small one.
There.
Boom!
But now...
I think it may be too fast?
This could be the breaking point.
Yeah, I knew it!
Okay, shit.
Oh, in that case, I don't even need that.
So really, what we wanna do...
We want one...
We want half of that speed, right?
That's like the optimum speed, I guess, before it starts to break down.
There's gonna be, like, one good answer here.
Definitely not that.
So now we get the speed by doing this.
Now we have the speed.
Here.
I think...
This is the speed we wanna end up with.
But if I put on a small one now, it's gonna...
Be double that speed.
And that's bad.
How do I do this in an elegant way?
Let me actually see these...
I mean, they use a shaft here.
I wish I could connect these not...
Like, diagonally, but...
Also, like, horizontally.
Yeah.
Okay.
But...
But then we're gonna end up with too much speed.
Isn't that too fast?
We're always gonna complain right now, right?
Let me see.
Oh, it's also the wrong...
Frickin'...
Woo!
This is rough.
Yeah, but...
The thing...
It doesn't connect to the big wheel.
Fuck it, my brain!
I mean, I could just make another...
One of these, but...
There's gotta be some way to do this.
We could just keep it ultra-simple.
And don't care about getting maximum speed.
That's an option.
I think this is the speed we wanna end up with.
Right?
This works beautifully.
When we finally connect it.
Here...
How do I...
Oh.
Oh, it's...
It's like I'm not...
There we go.
And then...
Small one.
No, it's too fast!
Can I really not connect two small wheels to each other?
Like...
Perpendicular?
Perpendicularly?
Why not?
Okay.
Let me try this again.
I guess it is a compact way to...
That way we don't actually go...
Diagonally with this.
Right?
Oh, wait.
That's the way to connect two small ones.
Ooh!
Hold on.
You can't do it with the small ones without the gearbox.
So let's get a little bit of speed first.
Here.
And then we do, I guess...
Vertical?
Now we need a small wheel.
Because that way we can connect two small wheels.
Ah!
Okay.
And then the mixer.
The thing is though, is this too slow?
Oh god.
I mean, it would say if it was too slow, but I also don't want it to be too slow.
I want it to be like...
As fast as it goes without braking.
Right?
So I already doubled the speed once.
I think if I double the speed again, that is when it's too fast.
That's the braking point.
But let's just...
Put the basin down.
There we go.
It's spinning, ladies and gentlemen!
That took a while.
In.
It's time for the saplings.
Wait a sec.
Something's going on.
Oops, wrong button.
Maybe I need more?
Oh!
Look at that mix!
Mixing it up!
Gimme.
We got the pulp!
Now!
Can we make paper with it?
Maybe.
Also, I must have clicked on something there.
Let me see here.
Uh...
Mechanical mixer.
Whoa!
Super heated.
A blaze cake.
Okay.
This is just normal heated.
Brass!
That's new.
Wait a minute.
This is...
More efficient.
Isn't it two of each?
Oh!
Okay, okay, okay.
We want to mix then.
Mix is good.
We like to mix.
Wheat flour is...
Yeah.
Wait, how did I make dough before?
Was I hand-cranking that shit?
I forgot how I did that.
Rooted dirt in water becomes mud.
Hmm.
Okay.
Well, I don't have the one of these, unfortunately.
But what is...
What is the point of...
Oh!
So, any type of greenery.
You put it in there with water and you get pulp.
All right.
The thing is, we don't know what to do with pulp.
Yet.
But I sure as shit know there's gonna be some way to use it.
Potentially to make paper.
That would be my dream.
I still can't look at this and think...
It's gotta be a better way.
Or not think that.
Because this is, um...
Yeah.
Kinda slow.
It's kinda nasty to look at.
Okay.
At least we figured that out.
Took a while.
Gearbox.
Should I try and couple some minecarts?
No, I think it's time we started working on the home a little bit.
Because this right here is a disgrace.
And...
That's not good.
I'm gonna go to bed.
And then we're gonna fix the flooring in this house.
Yo, I actually kinda like that look.
Weirdly.
Before I pick him up, we're gonna take this.
Now we take it.
Kinda cool that you have to sort of...
Like manual labor, you know?
Multiple stages of processing here.
Right now it's manual, but it will be automated.
I think that should be enough.
I'm gonna actually use this for flooring.
As crazy as it sounds.
Because I think it...
It just looks...
Incredible.
Like, what a block.
Get rid of all of this.
Thank god these don't...
Prevent me from destroying the floor, huh?
Would've been so annoying.
Kinda wanna make, uh...
Whatchamacallit.
Andeside...
Stairs.
You know?
So it fits.
Wait, wait.
Maybe I can.
No.
I was trying to right click on it.
It's cool that the edges sort of blend together here.
You see that?
No!
I don't have enough?
That's crazy.
Ah, but...
Hey!
You come with me.
The toolbox and I are gonna go on a little adventure.
Actually, no we're not.
We're staying right home.
We're staying here.
Oh, I need, I need, uh...
Bone meal.
I don't have that.
But I can get it!
Dude!
I'm such a genius.
Watch this.
Composter!
Oh, wait.
How do I make a composter?
Uh...
Oh, shit!
I don't know!
Okay, fine.
I guess I won't do it.
It's fine though.
I'll go to the forest and start cutting down shit.
It's gonna be good.
And you know...
Oh!
You know what we're gonna do?
We're gonna prioritize the nasty trees.
You see this one right here?
That...
Is a nasty tree!
Ew!
Oh, wait.
Put that there.
And now we're gonna go like this.
Crank that shit!
Tell me that isn't the sexiest thing you've ever seen in your life.
Wow, these really fell all over the place.
Damn.
Okay.
Holy...
You come with me.
Actually, you come with me as well.
Maybe it's not actually...
smart to have...
to carry this around.
It's easier to just put these down.
Immediately.
Yeah, that's a nasty tree.
The problem is, it's spewing it on top here too.
It's all over now.
Let's do a couple more.
Where's the...
There's a big tree right there.
Oh, that's a big one.
Crank that shit!
This is the best thing ever.
I can't wait to mow down an entire forest.
And watch all the animals with no home scatter.
Oh, just the thought of that...
Gets me going, you know?
Making people homeless.
I'm gonna do one more.
Uno masu.
Where do we have a nice fat tree?
I think we...
just about did it.
Alright, I'm happy with that.
Oh, there's one more over here.
No fat trees in my neighborhood.
Those get eradicated.
And the cool part is, we get free apples while doing it too.
Kinda wanna try and smash an apple with the press.
You know?
See if we get apple...
pulp.
Maybe we can make an apple pie.
The cool thing is, we even get all the saplings at the same time.
Very nice.
Okay.
We just got a lot of wood.
Really easily.
Feels good, yo.
There's an issue with what I just did though.
I have to put them all down again.
And then I have to Mr. Miyagi them.
Every single one.
It's fine though.
But, here's the thing.
We also don't have any of these.
Hey Stuart!
Did you bring me wares from the east?
Yo!
I kinda need that!
Dark oak sapling!
This is the big tree!
You want five for that though.
Nah.
I mean, I don't even have the money.
So, I'm sorry Stuart.
I'm poor!
I don't got the dough.
I got one dough in here you can have.
Flooring is almost done.
God, that looks good.
Dude, look at this floor!
Tell me that isn't spectacular looking.
I'm in love with that.
Celebratory ding.
Really want to use the chute right now.
Boink!
And then I can...
Oh, I can't.
But I can still like this, you know?
I like that.
That's good.
What do I bring with me?
Cause I wanna go get some andesite.
Wait a minute.
Hold up.
See, now I'm thinking.
Mechanical drill, huh?
Can we get a...
Crank that shit going on somehow here?
In some kind of smart way.
Cause I wanna...
I wanna collect that andesite.
In a very smart way.
Put this dirt down instead.
Pulp goes in there.
I also probably need to bring some proper armor.
This one I still don't quite understand.
I think we need another piece for that one.
Put this on instead for safety measure.
Now, the diving boots give me one armor compared to...
Two!
So let's just bring...
The normal shoes for now.
Yips.
Ah!
Can I?
Aww.
That's too bad.
Unless...
No.
I was trying to put them in directly via the UI.
Wait.
So...
It says zero on this one.
And zero on this one.
So I guess this is like reserved for these tools.
These slots are reserved.
So if I pick up...
This one and I go like this...
They immediately go where they're supposed to.
Hmm.
Oh!
You know what?
Let me think how that can be used.
Let's say I'm out exploring.
Wait, what is this little...
Why does my inventory look so elongated?
What's happening?
Oh, that is just the size of my inventory.
It's just when it's by itself like that, it looks really weird.
It doesn't look normal.
I got bamboozled.
But let's say I'm out exploring, right?
And I reserve these spots for something like...
The stuff I don't want to pick up, right?
Let's say bones...
Or...
You know, rotten meat.
Stuff like that.
As soon as I pick those up, I can easily just click alt on them.
And they all go in here.
Hmm?
Not bad.
I think that could be used.
Let's get rid of these.
I'm gonna keep this at home.
Hmm.
That one too.
So the mechanical drill.
We need a...
I need a...
Manual crank for that.
But the thing is, it's only gonna destroy the block in front of it.
So...
I still haven't cracked that one, how to figure that out.
How to...
Essentially just keep it going.
You know?
In one direction.
So I don't really know.
Yet.
For now...
Let's just...
Not worry about it.
We bring the shield.
There we go.
Got the axe.
Shield goes in.
And I have food.
I should have food somewhere.
Wait, where are my meats at?
Did I put them in here?
I did.
Silly me.
Nothing else I need, right?
Nope.
Maybe some more dirt for ascension.
Let's go get some...
More andesite.
Also gotta get another bit.
Kinda wish that ding was even louder.
Gotta get some more experience.
Ooh.
Just had a horizontal medicine.
Briefly.
Oh, I forgot my...
Torches.
Now I'm thinking...
Maybe there's a way to...
Create cheap explosives.
That was one of my preferred ways of mining.
So if I can do that in an even better way...
I would be much pleased.
Also, hold on.
Wasn't there a way to...
Was it this one?
Wait, let me think.
If we can get flint...
There's like a path here, you know?
Where if I can get a good source of flint and gravel...
Gravel can be made by taking cobblestone and going...
On them.
No, going...
That's the thing, right?
What did that?
Why did I see that?
Oh, the millstone.
That's the one.
Here.
Cobblestone in.
Gravel out.
But then again, why wouldn't I just collect gravel then?
Maybe because cobblestone is easier to find.
That would make sense.
And...
Ripstone...
Really gotta do this when I find bones.
So essentially, one cobblestone becomes one flint.
That's not a bad deal at all.
Is it?
If you get that going.
I just need one stack, really.
Don't need that much.
But since I'm here...
Let's go kill a couple skeletons so we can get some bone.
What's up, dude?
Should I leave you alone?
Yeah.
I broke my ankle.
I was trying to hit the water.
Mistakes were made.
Problem is I don't have torches, right?
But I just need a little bit...
of coal, then I can make them.
I must have left some somewhere.
In fact, I do need to collect more coal.
I'm running out at home.
What's this way?
There we go.
Now I can take this...
make sticks...
Gravel!
That's the one we need, right?
Which one was it?
Gravel becomes...
flint.
God, I already forgot where I saw...
Was it millstone?
Here we go.
That's the one.
And we needed flint to get andeside.
Maybe it is worth it to pick up a little bit of this.
Just a bit.
It's easy to get.
Especially if we get a better shovel.
More sink!
I actually don't need that much.
I have a bunch already.
My dream right now is to make that...
Damn windmill on top of my house.
And have it...
Supply power for my daily needs.
I'm a simple man with simple dreams.
But then after that I will have more dreams.
There's a skeleton somewhere.
Which is good news.
Because one bone...
Becomes a lot of bone meal when you...
When you churn it.
And I intend to churn.
Lots of these.
Nice.
Now where's this skeleton at?
I think he's in an adjacent cave.
Oh, one thing I need to focus on while I'm down here.
Is to look for all kinds of...
Special blocks.
That I haven't mined yet.
Because...
Maybe some of them will unlock...
Um...
That one component that I need.
That allows things to rotate.
On its axis.
Wanna fight me?
Come on then.
Oh god.
Would also be kinda sweet to make...
Some diamonds.
I do wanna try and make a diamond block.
I'm sure that will unlock something.
And then I gotta focus on making my house a little more presentable.
So when I come home we have enough to make the...
Flooring.
I do wanna make a roof that isn't as shit as it is right now.
And maybe also a little bit of, you know, furniture placement.
Make it look nice and homey.
We're gonna put the Dell...
The Dell.
The Dell laptop is gonna go on...
A barrel.
No.
The bell is gonna go on a barrel.
The bell barrel.
Where are you?
Is there like a tiny mini cave?
Right in the center here.
Okay, I'm coming and I'm gonna find you.
I know you're right here.
What?
Are you downstairs?
Oh!
Oh shit!
Carrot on a stick.
A classic.
I thought I was wearing the boots for a second.
It wants to make me fall down.
Sink.
Deadly combo.
Did he just damage himself?
Somehow?
That looked weird.
This stuff up there is...
Weird.
Still haven't discovered the use case.
Now...
The existence of this though...
Has to mean that...
There's crystals nearby.
Yo, I kinda wanna try and mix this or press it.
See what happens then.
You know what?
I've had it.
Let's go down.
Let's do the Minecraft thing.
I gotta get diamonds somehow.
And this way I can also get the more rare blocks.
Ooh, that reminds me!
I gotta go to the nether!
Surely there's weird combinations to be made with items from there.
Right?
We got some diorite here.
Always taking iron.
Oh, here we go.
Cobble deep slate.
Oh wait, I'm not doing this efficiently.
We're getting deeper.
Like who knows, maybe there's entirely new blocks when you go deep enough.
That sink.
My diamond pickaxe is...
Almost destroyed already.
I forgot how terrible they are without enchantments.
Starting to hear enemies, that's a good sign.
Make a noise.
Ooh, not that noise, please.
I'm going here.
I can feel it.
Say something?
Ooh, we're close.
Where are you?
Are you down here?
I can hear you.
I can smell you!
Oh shit.
Thank God it wasn't that big of a fall there, huh?
Holy crap.
Uh oh.
Here they come.
Wow.
Oh, I nearly had a heart attack.
Everything's fine though.
We are in control.
Of the situation.
Ooh, we got diamonds!
Diamonds, baby.
There's more!
Oh, this guy has a special bow.
That's cool.
Wanna dance?
Oh, I missed.
Good night.
Oh yeah, this is what I'm talking about.
Sustain me with diamonds.
These guys want a piece of me.
Sweet.
Very needed.
Yeah.
See, this axe right here is all you need for combat.
Who needs a sword?
Not me.
Let's make a lapis lazuli block as well.
Is that gold?
We need that.
I have a feeling gold is gonna be big.
In fact, I never went back with lapis lazuli, I don't think.
Because I died.
And lost it.
The first time I found it.
Level 15.
We're nearly back where we were.
Did I bring the toolbox?
I really should have brought it just for storage.
I don't know why I didn't.
I even said I wanted to do that.
Oh, here we go.
Ran it?
Whoa, that's like a million different things I just unlocked.
Be popular.
Nothing else I want to do here.
Excuse me, Mr. Spider.
Are you stuck?
I'm sorry.
Soon time to make a bow.
Why did I not go down here?
Looks very promising.
Don't even think I have much redstone at home.
Hello?
You are right here.
Hello!
There you are.
Oh!
Wow.
Let me make it easy for you.
Oh, shit!
Oh!
Oh, fuck!
Ah!
Holy...
Focus, focus, focus!
Focus!
Calm down, calm down.
Man, that could have gone the opposite way for sure.
I handled that like a champ.
Oh, you know what?
Let's grab some lava!
Oh!
We can use that for things.
Sweet.
Uh...
Aw, man.
I wish I had water with me.
So I could make some obsidian.
Too bad.
We lost the shield.
Can I make a new one?
For sure I cannot, because I didn't bring enough wood!
That's why you bring wood, guys!
I have learned my lesson once again.
Or I guess I have not learned my lesson once again.
Okay, this is my...
cue to get out of here.
Let me grab this one and then leave.
There's someone right here.
Ish.
Hold on, maybe I'll take a quick peek.
Oh!
Hello!
Thought I fell down.
Nice!
Good, good, good, good.
Yo, I wonder what happens if I put gunpowder...
on the bonk machine.
Is it gonna go boom?
I gotta try that.
Oh, oh, oh!
Nope!
Man, you came from the skies, didn't you?
Fuck you!
Evasive action!
MLG!
Oh, I'm so good.
I handled that.
Oh, look at all this!
Good thing I stayed, huh?
So happy I didn't go back.
Is that...
Wait a sec.
Yeah!
Yes, yes, yes!
I need you.
Come with me.
I don't need this anymore.
Oh, that is wonderful.
That is wonderful.
Uh...
You are grown.
You are grown!
I think that...
Yeah, that was it.
Okay!
Not bad.
Now I can finally make what I've been wanting to make for a long time.
Uh...
Spyglass?
Wait, we need something else for that.
Glass!
Of course!
We need a glass and we need a spy, right?
Both are needed.
So, I came from... where?
Oh, there's more.
Oh my god.
Look at all this...
diamond!
This cave is the best.
Also, I'm running out of torches.
It really is time to get out now.
Let me just have a quick look.
Ooh!
Nah.
Okay, we're getting out.
Dude, I thought that was a portal at the end.
But that's just the...
The diamond place.
Or not the diamond place, the...
What?
What's it called?
Amethyst place.
Uh...
Don't go down.
Go up.
We're getting out of here now.
Ascension!
What's up, guys?
See ya!
You wish you could get to me, but you can't.
We're going straight up.
Okay, guys.
Oh!
Oh, shit!
Take me to a surface.
Oh, man.
That is scary, isn't it?
Gotta...
Kill you.
Okay.
We can ascend a little bit.
Dude, this...
Wait a second.
I just realized something.
How the fuck am I gonna get home?
Uh-oh!
Let's hope I get out somewhere recognizable.
I was so busy collecting all this stuff...
That I totally forgot to...
Worry about the single most important thing in Minecraft.
Which is where the hell you are.
Guys, it's gonna be night!
It's night outside.
It's night.
Watch me be right.
Piss!
Why...
It's like...
Everything is conspiring against me.
Okay, don't panic.
Where are you?
No way!
Look at this!
Look where we are!
That is almost too perfect.
You know what this means, right?
We're gonna make...
A cave...
Uh...
Shortcut from here.
Down.
Isn't that nice?
What's up, steward?
What you brought me?
Oh.
Nothing new, eh?
Very good.
Okay, man.
Let's have a look then.
Spy?
Yes!
I got it!
Boink!
Give me this one.
Finally!
Oh, man.
What a feeling.
So incredibly useful.
Wait, hold on.
Is this...
Maybe I'm smoking something?
Is this zooming more than it used to?
This is like a mega zoom.
Usually it doesn't zoom in so much that you can actually see stuff like this up here.
I think they may have enhanced that.
Uh, okay.
Well, we got lava now.
And we got...
Stuff to make the floor...
Complete.
Which is...
And the site.
And then we needed...
Uh, this.
Granite...
Yeah, let's make a granite slab, I guess.
And...
Here it is.
Make them all.
Okay.
I already put a bunch outside.
Dup, dump, dump, dump, dump, dump, dump, dump, dump, dump, dump, dump, dump.
That actually kinda looks cool.
Having that little...
You know?
Oh, that's why I can't do it.
There we go.
Looks like some kinda shipping container.
Made of...
Wood.
From the side.
Nice.
This house will be insane.
Dude, this floor is sexy as hell.
Love that.
We gotta fix this here.
Gotta at least make this look presentable, huh?
I actually wonder.
Let's not go overboard with the anticide casing.
Enough is enough!
Don't be tempted.
Normal wood.
Which I do have a lot of somewhere.
Over here, maybe?
Yes, sir.
Ah, so much better, huh?
And for the ceiling... I need a thing on that one.
Oh, one thing I also want to do, of course, is to get some sand and make glass.
I'm sure something's gotta happen with glass, of all things.
Let me quickly grab that wallace over there.
I see it.
What if I get?
Cheers, guys.
Hand me that sand.
Aw, you know what?
I feel like fishing a little bit, actually.
This right here, I hate.
We have to fix that.
It's clean now.
This sand we can grab.
Oh.
Um.
Actually, it's fine.
Make some sticks.
Make a table.
Shovel time!
Much better.
Ugh!
Brother!
What the fuck is this?
What actually happened here?
Did a bomb go off?
Brother- Ew!
I'm actually gonna take care of that off-stream.
I'm not even kidding.
I will do off-stream mining.
I will go over there.
And I will fix those crimes.
Oh.
Inventory full.
We don't need diorite.
Okay, why did I collect that much sand?
I didn't need that much.
All I wanted was to just test what sand did.
Oh, we got a dude.
I gotta kill him.
How can I make an improved EDP?
IEDP.
Improvised off the land.
What's up, son?
What you got?
We got nothing.
What's up?
Wow, didn't even drop anything.
Man, they really need to calm down.
I was considering killing that chicken to get some feathers.
You know what?
I'm actually gonna do it.
Because what if that feather is the key to making more feathers?
Maybe you can breed feathers in this game.
Oh!
We should plant a carrot for sure!
What do I not need here?
Ah, fuck these slaps.
I guess I could make the roof out of slaps.
The world is called contemporary world, right?
Nowadays...
I wanna make it out of glass, now that I have the sand.
Actually, yeah.
Let's make it out of glass.
But first...
Uh, we should put this guy to work.
There we go.
In.
Oh, what's happening here?
Oh, okay.
Uh-huh.
Maybe there's a use for rotten flesh, finally.
Should we try and...
Do this.
Rotten flesh soup, go!
Mix that shit!
You probably need water in there.
Eh, hold on.
Or...
No, no, no, no, no, no, no.
I really need to go to bed.
How...
Why did you explode?
Good thing I brought dirt.
There's no way I'm letting this hole stay like this.
We fix it immediately.
There.
Spick and span, nothing happened.
Nothing ever took place.
Right there.
Feathers!
Let's make an arrow.
We got some flint.
Do I really need this?
Oh, you also need a stick, of course.
You're so demanding.
Fourteen arrows, not bad.
Now we just need a bow.
And we gotta figure out a quick and easy...
Not too quick and not too easy...
Item situation storage...
Management thingy.
You know what I mean?
Good.
Lava buckets...
I do need to deposit that somewhere.
Do we have a little lava...
Area here?
We can put you there for now, I guess.
Just until I come back.
Okay, grab the water.
We're gonna make rotten fish soup now.
Wait, what?
Wasn't this supposed to be higher up?
Why is this so low?
Wait, give me that.
What?
Hold on.
Why...
Wait, I don't understand what's happening here.
Why can't this do that?
What's wrong?
Okay, now we fill it up.
Yeah, see?
Now it's filled.
Oh, I forgot to sleep.
Okay, now I can take this.
Put this back.
And you are on fire.
What's up, man?
Now we put rotten meat?
Mix!
Okay, fine.
Let's try with...
Oh, dude.
Oh, it's not gonna...
It's not gonna do it?
Okay.
I was kinda hoping it would explode, you know?
That would be too funny.
My inventory is a mess, of course, like always.
Let's work on the roof, actually.
That's the next part.
Ah, fine!
I'll do some fucking stairs.
I always end up with stairs, don't I?
When I make roof.
Ah, but then I have to think about the frickin'...
No.
I mean, it's good to have some stairs.
Also, fill this up.
Grab...
Oh my god, my inventory!
Grab it!
Emergency!
Fuck it.
Fill it!
I feel so much better.
Wow.
Let's go plant this carrot.
I need to walk around with the...
with the little hatch thingy.
Make some bread as well.
Why is this not operating?
Because it's full.
Good.
Anything else that needs...
You know, I should blast the shit.
What am I doing?
Smooth stone, huh?
No, that's a slab.
How do I just make...
Smooth stone?
I forgot how to do that.
Is it just to cook it?
Something about that, right?
This is gonna make...
What?
Let's see.
I think it's smooth stone.
Okay, now it's stone, but we can make it smooth.
Oh!
Something new, maybe?
No.
Doesn't look like it.
Wait, why do I not remember how to do that?
Let's try this.
No, this is gonna make it cracked, right?
What?
No, that's gonna make it...
It's only gonna make it cracked if it's bricks.
This is not bricks.
This is...
Bricks and minifigs.
Wait, no.
Put this up here.
I need a couple more smooth stone, actually.
Now that I got glass!
Come on, show me something!
That's new.
Oh!
What's that?
I thought this was an eye.
Oh!
Look at that!
Together with back tank allows the wielder to breathe underwater for an extended amount of time.
Provides the water breathing effect slowly draining air pressure from the back tank.
That is so freaking cool.
We gotta crank that shit, but not manually.
Watch this.
We're gonna use some of this energy we got here.
In fact, maybe we can make it go ultra mega fast.
It's actually so exciting now, because I'm gonna be doing something useful with the gears.
Where are my gears?
Here?
Here.
Yeah.
And then?
Let me think.
It needs to go like that way, right?
So...
Small gear.
That's fine.
And then?
I forgot the...
No, I didn't.
Oh, it's from the top!
It's not from the side.
Whoops.
So...
I mean, I do want that speed, I guess.
Let's keep the speed.
And make a...
Big one?
Oh.
Oh, it's collapsing with...
Oh, I see.
Maybe I just take it from here.
That's probably easier.
Let me put a big one on top.
And dude, we...
Oh.
Oh!
No, thanks.
What's up, guys?
How's it hanging?
I don't have a shield!
Uh, what?
Good, good, good, good.
Now I'm ready.
Oh, they were leaving!
Oh, ow!
Haha, dumbass!
You suck.
Owned you.
Voluntary exile.
I don't remember that achievement at all.
What was that?
Not sure.
I wanted to go get shafts.
That was the whole point.
Because if you have shafts, you can just go...
Downwards into the tank.
Ain't no way I'm hand-cranking that shit.
Oh!
It's too fast!
Okay.
Aw, man.
I thought I could go...
Omega fast with that.
I guess we can do it like this, then.
And put you...
Ah, bad spot.
Put the little guy...
Here.
And then we put this guy right there.
Oh!
What?
That's...
Hold on.
This contraption is overstressed.
Add more sources or slow down the comp...
Oh!
More sources!
You say.
It's not overstressed because...
It's not this one that's overstressed.
No.
It is this one that's overstressed.
This one is causing the rest to be overstressed.
I'm feeling overstressed.
You know what?
I have an idea, guys.
And it's a really good one.
Are you ready?
It's actually so beautiful.
I can't believe I didn't think about it earlier.
We're making another water wheel.
And we're gonna use the same water stream but on the other side.
Huh?
Not bad.
Look at that.
Now I wonder...
What if I were to do something cheeky like this?
Oh.
For some reason I thought they would meet...
Oh, but yeah.
I guess they're moving against each other.
Also called opposite.
So let's do this.
And then a small one.
Here.
Good enough for me.
This should work.
Look at that!
That's being cranked.
Hehe.
Yo.
This is fantastic.
I love the idea of having this sort of pressurized tank on your back that you have to refill with power that you create yourself.
I think that is genius game design.
That is amazing.
Very nice.
But now I'm thinking...
Let's go make it...
Make it go faster.
This is not quite fast enough, is it?
In fact...
We can even go downwards with it.
Like that.
And then here.
And boom!
Even faster cranking.
This is a mess, obviously.
This is gonna be fixed in the future.
This is just for, you know...
Learning purposes, mostly.
Sun is going down.
Go to sleep.
I gotta make a bow.
A proper one.
I think it's time.
Oh, we also got bones now.
Let's try this!
Where's my mix-a-roo?
Mix, mix, mix.
Didn't I have a mix...
Here?
Did I get rid of that?
I think I got rid of it.
Why would I do that?
Oh, because I wanted it in my house.
And can we still not fix that one right now?
Hold on.
I need to make this now.
I'm going crazy.
Sales.
Let me see this again.
What is that thing?
Hmm.
It's this thing!
It's exactly this thing on that icon.
Blocks that count towards the strength of a windmill contraption when assembled.
Each of these have equal efficiency in doing so.
Hmm.
I don't know.
Also, I was doing this.
I wanted to make three of these smooth stones for some reason.
Or I needed smooth stone for something.
I forgot what it was.
What was it?
Something about...
Also, I unlocked some new stuff, didn't I?
I got distracted and then...
What?!
Oak window!
That sounds frickin' amazing.
Stonecutter?
Maybe that does something.
Other than cut stones.
Haha!
Wait, what?!
Hold on, a laser pointer?!
Now you have my attention.
What are you talking about?
Casing and shard.
To focus it, I guess.
Casing, I think we have somewhere.
Do we not?
No way I used it all.
Ah, there it is.
Heh.
Okay, what the hell is this?
In fact, before I look at this, I kinda just wanna see...
What it looks like here.
So obviously that's redstone.
Max casting distance?
Yo, what the fuck?!
That is so satisfying?!
Nice!
We need power.
Torch.
Requires a stick.
Which I do possess.
What?
Oh, wait a sec.
Is this a way to transmit redstone signal?
If I have a receiver?
Huh?
Holy shit.
I get it.
I think.
We grab the signal here and we do whatever we want with it.
Dude.
That is so freaking cool!
And you can...
So I'm guessing this is blocks.
100 meters.
That is amazing.
Big fan of that.
Although part of me was hoping that it would be a deathly laser that I could use to just murder enemies with.
But I'll take it!
This is also very cool.
But there was a lot of other things we unlocked.
Show me.
These ones!
Engineer's goggles.
Sheet.
And some kind of glass and string.
Sounds easy enough.
Are we doing glass?
Not yet.
I think I have some glass?
Oh, speaking of sheets.
I gotta press this.
Press the gold.
Amazing.
That is such a good design on that too.
All this just kind of makes sense.
It's all coming together.
Then the glass.
There it is.
And string.
Engineers.
Goggles!
Whoa!
Kitted out!
I'm a real engineer.
Augments your hut with miscellaneous information about placed components.
When looking at blocks.
Kinetic components show added stress impact or capacity.
Stressometers show statistics of their attached kinetic network.
Some other blocks reveal information such as item and fluid content.
That is freaking amazing.
Kinetic stress capacity.
256...
speed units?
Never seen that unit before.
128...
SU at current speed.
What does that say?
Okay.
Also, they just kind of look cool.
I want to walk around with them.
Makes me feel like an engineer.
We can even put on the...
wrench.
Look at that.
Now we're ready.
Are you fully charged?
Almost.
Let's go try it.
Haha.
Cool.
Let me see actually.
Oh my god.
It actually is like a backpack thingy.
Look at that.
That's amazing.
Okay.
Here we go.
Ready for the depths.
Oh, there's a timer.
Nice.
And we can apparently mine faster as well, you say?
Oh, man.
You know what this means, guys?
This means we can go exploring caves completely safely.
Because there's not going to be any monsters down here.
Holy crap.
Especially if we put on the boots as well.
We can walk down here as if we're...
Stuart.
I know you want to be a diver as well.
But you gotta get a scoop of tank and...
a diving helmet before you do that stuff.
No, you can't have mine.
I will need those later.
Very cool.
Let's put that in...
the toolbox.
There.
And...
this one.
I mean, this is like made for this, isn't it?
Not bad, huh?
We're gonna carry this around with us.
There's stuff over here.
Okay, so with these amethyst shards...
What else can I do?
I mean, let's try and make a loom.
Man, I have barely used this, actually.
I almost don't remember how this works.
I guess you need some kind of color here.
A banner of some sort.
And...
something there.
Whatever that is.
Not entirely sure.
Chain conveyor.
Are we gonna...
actually be able to move chains around?
Kinetic stress capacity.
Small.
So I guess that simply means this one will not be able to output a lot of power.
Because it cannot handle a lot of stress.
I need to see this.
Whoa!
Double windows?
What is that?
Double?
Oh no, okay.
Oh...
Okay, then.
We definitely need to do this.
Window.
Oh, it's a pane!
Right!
I get it now.
And it's glass.
And glass breaks.
Dang.
Uh, now I kinda regret making this...
floor at this level.
Because the windows are gonna look like shit.
Hmm.
Not good.
That's bad.
Not...
that bad, is it?
Wait, can I open this?
I thought they were one of those flapjack windows that...
you know, the old school windows...
you know, where the woman in a dress...
she just finished singing, she had animals on her...
shoulders, and she opens the window with both her arms...
outwards.
You know what I mean?
But it's not that.
Looks cool though.
Let me try the other thing I have.
Oh, it's the exact same, just...
different.
Ha ha ha ha!
Yeah, that looks good.
You can even do this.
This, obviously, is gonna be fixed.
I like this though.
Maybe we even add some stairs here.
Not really feeling that.
It's just kinda too...
high, isn't it?
Maybe we can make some slaps.
One good use for them.
Oh boy, though.
Oh!
Whoa!
What the fuck?!
That's, that's one of the things I need!
That's a lot!
Aviator's Goggles.
Hold on.
Schematic table?
Say what now?
That's what I need!
This is what I need!
Ponder, yes!
Let's ponder on that.
Mechanical bearings.
Attached to the block in front of them.
Yes?
Upon receiving rotational force, it will assemble it into a rotating contraption.
Okay.
So you give it force from below.
Right, and they're gonna stick together.
How do you make this superglue though?
Probably out of the slime, right?
Would make sense.
Yeah.
I mean, that's nice.
But I think I know what to do with this.
Check it out.
That's just there.
Fred is there.
Where was the thing I just had?
Am I drunk?
What the...
Hold
on a minute.
What just happened?
I'm so confused.
Hold on, so...
Oh!
It's here.
Huh?
Movement mode?
Always place when stopped.
That looks like a windmill symbol.
Only place when anchor destroyed.
I mean, yeah, you can have something that rotates on top.
But except...
Imagine you have windmill thingies on this, right?
Oh.
What's this?
What?
When stopped, the bearing will place the structure at the nearest grid-aligned angle.
Okay.
So we don't want it to be stopped.
This behavior can be modified using the value panel.
It can be configured never to revert to solid blocks, or only near the angle it started at.
Tell me more.
Whenever mechanical bearings are themselves part of a moving structure...
Yes!
Go on!
Oh no!
Oh!
Whoa!
That's fucking cool!
Yo!
Alright!
That looks amazing!
But I know what to look at now.
We gotta look at the sails again.
If I can find them.
Sales...
Yeah...
As you can tell, I'm having trouble with my current inventory layout.
Mainly because my current inventory layout is...
terrible.
That's why I'm having trouble.
These sails have fallen off the face of the earth!
You cannot tell me that I just missed the sails.
It's not these.
What?
Where?
Never mind.
I'm blind.
Alright!
Let's look at him.
Okay.
Let's look at this shit!
Oh, I get it!
Fuck this stupid wheel!
Boo!
No!
And now...
Windmill mode engage!
Wait...
Hold on!
Technical issues!
Give me a moment!
Go on!
Wait, hold on!
Is that even the same freaking block?
Dude, it's not even the same freaking block!
You...
Gotta be kidding me!
I have been trolled by this multiple times now!
It's this!
It's even called a windmill fucking bearing!
Shit!
Here we go!
Huh?
Oh, wait!
The other way!
Right click the...
Bearing with an empty hand to attach the structure you just built...
In front of it!
Wait a second!
I probably should have looked at this!
Oh!
But, but, but, uh...
Why can I not make the windmill like this?
Oh!
Wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait!
Maybe it does need a thingy underneath.
Right click the bearing with an empty...
Oh!
I thought it meant right click these fucking things to adjust the direction thingy.
There we go!
We got it!
Very nice!
And now we can grab that motion...
You know what?
I understand how it works.
I understand everything.
Everything is clear.
Clearest day.
I know where to put this.
It's gonna be great.
You'll see.
I'm actually so happy we finally got this.
And the whole thing came...
From the worst block in the game.
The slab.
The slab was the one thing...
That broke the case wide open.
No wonder I found out so late.
Because nobody makes slabs willingly.
Unless they...
Have lost their minds.
Okay.
Let's go to bed.
No, it's actually morning, isn't it?
I think there's a wild animal outside my window.
Someone just went...
So it's probably a fox.
Isn't that what they say?
I learned that from Red Dead Redemption.
Okay, are you ready for the innovation of the century?
This is gonna blow your damn mind.
Get out of here.
Stuart!
I'm relocating your flower.
You'll have to take care of it down here.
Now.
Mechanical bearing.
Let's figure out where this needs to be.
Where do we want it?
I probably need to think...
What do I want in here with that?
Let me think.
What do I use a lot?
Maybe this press...
could be nice to have.
We could even have a windmill room.
And then we can have a guy in there...
playing music.
And it's gonna be the best song you've ever heard in your life.
I make a little windmill room...
here.
But then the whole thing becomes square again.
We don't like that, do we?
I could also just...
YOLO it.
You know what?
I'm gonna YOLO it.
YOLO!
Make a hole in the roof.
And...
you know what?
I am a fan of making the roof...
this way.
Like, ultra flat.
Oh yeah, I was making slabs because I wanted to make the roof.
Let's actually just finish that thought.
At the same time...
Ah, but the slabs are probably gonna mess up the whole situation.
Because you know why?
Because they're slabs.
But we'll have to see.
Good.
Now, I need to decide.
How will...
How will this look?
Right, okay, so that doesn't actually do anything for me.
Ah, rip.
Oh, I gotta...
Customers!
At the door!
That's what I think of.
You know, I am tempted to use this as the roof as well.
But maybe let's not overdo it.
We could use stone to try something mega weird.
Is that too weird?
We could also use sails.
No, I can't.
Not a good idea.
How does this look?
Let's say I were to do this.
How does it feel?
Dude, it actually feels good!
You cannot tell me that doesn't feel good.
Doesn't that tingle inside?
Look at the way it sort of contrasts with...
Oh, yeah.
But the problem is gonna be the top of the roof.
From the outside.
That's gonna look ugly AF.
We'll have to fix that.
Oh!
Waze.
Bit of a waste for glass, but...
Could make a dirt roof.
Yes.
And then join down there with the dirt.
Tell me I have more dirt.
Or do I need to go collect that?
It's gonna connect down like...
It's like a little...
It's like a half hobbit house, okay?
It's gonna be super cozy.
You go in there, you have like a windmill going and...
You're sitting there in the reading corner and you're sipping wine and having fun.
Oh, yeah!
Let's put down the thing.
Are you ready, kids?
Shit.
That is the wrong way.
Let's try that again.
Now, can I place it like this?
Yeah!
Good.
And then on top of that, we go like here.
Here.
I'm even gonna...
What do you think?
Just for argument's sake.
Let's do this.
And put on the sails.
That's ugly as hell.
I don't like that.
How can I make it pretty?
Do I shaft?
I don't even know if I can do that.
Can I even shaft?
Nah, you know what?
Let's put it all the way up top.
Keep it simple.
No need to overthink things.
Because we can just use a rod.
Extending downwards.
And then everyone is happy.
Turd!
Where are you?
What the fuck?
That must mean I don't have it.
And I have to do this first.
Then I have to remove it.
Oh, yeah.
I guess it didn't matter then.
Windmill bearing.
Boom!
Shit!
There we go.
Okay, now.
There.
And now.
Very elegant.
Definitely one more.
Wait, am I not missing some?
I'm missing some.
Oh, I probably made symmetric sails out of some of them.
Sail.
You can make them in different ways.
Oh, you can make them out of these?
Well, in that case.
That's an easy choice.
Yes.
That is amazing!
Guys!
That is incredible.
And you know what?
We can make it prettier.
Just tell me these are not gonna fall off when I do this.
Maybe I have to do this first.
Wait, what?
Stop!
Oh my god.
Empty hand, you say?
Okay.
Here.
Remove.
That's better looking!
Oh my god.
This is insanely good.
Go.
Spin for me!
It's spinning.
Now...
We find out where it is.
There it is.
And then we do...
Watch!
Wait, what?
No, no, no, no, no.
This...
Into...
This!
Shit!
Oh, maybe I need the...
Oh.
I need this on first.
Ah.
Dude, that looks insane-o style.
I need wheels.
Oh, no.
Yeah, this is what I feared.
This is why I said we need a...
Windmill room.
Hmm.
We could also make this the windmill room.
And then relocate a little bit.
Or we use it as an aesthetic choice.
And say...
We like...
What we're seeing.
And we want more of that.
Where's the rest of my small wheels?
There's no way I use them all.
I don't believe that.
Okay, I'm gonna slowly look...
And see if I can see them.
They're not here.
There they are!
Got them!
So now...
It's...
I freaking love it!
Oh, man.
And then...
Now we rot it.
We millstone it.
No, wait.
That's not how that works.
Scratch that!
Who says the millstone needs to be eye-level?
Nobody ever said that!
Watch this!
Ah, but that doesn't make any sense either, does it?
Then what we're gonna do instead is...
I take this wheel...
Interesting.
Very interesting.
Yeah?
I mean, I...
Yeah, okay.
I do like...
Wait, I'm doing the mistake again.
That's not how that works.
Stop it!
It needs to go in from the side!
Damn it.
I mean, there's an obvious answer here, but it's ugly as hell.
Good enough for now!
Sue me.
Shit works!
You know what?
It's actually, um...
It's an aesthetic choice.
It's like a rustic look, the way you get to see the wheels and the innards of the machine.
The intricacies of the genius behind it is on full display.
Everyone who comes into my house is gonna be like, Ooh, you're so smart!
I'm gonna look at my bookshelf of all the books I've never read.
They're gonna see this and they're gonna be impressed.
Okay, let's fill this up.
Wait a minute.
Could I have done this better?
I feel like there's...
Wait!
I'm...
The realization is dawning on me.
Oh, but wait, you can't do that.
Okay, never mind.
I keep forgetting the rules with these.
Wait a second.
Wait a second!
Have thou ever heard of a gearbox?
A vertical gearbox.
See, that's good.
The problem is...
It's too thick.
This is a chonky boy.
I don't like when it's chonky like that.
Like, I'm gonna hit my head when I run into that.
You know?
I would rather see the intricacies of the machine and the genius behind it.
This is what I live for.
Also, where the hell are all my gears?
There's no way I only have one.
What happened to my other one?
Never mind.
Ah, I can't do that.
Oh, wait.
I just used them to make the thing.
That's why.
Good thing I can make infinite of these.
Here.
And here.
Nope.
Wait, I feel like...
Didn't I do this with Les before?
I almost hit my head still though.
That's not pretty.
I wonder though, so...
If I use my...
Wait, was there a way to open this in a cool way?
Right click.
Oh, this is when it's down.
Okay.
Let me just play around with this.
Oh, so...
Oh, you reverse the 90 when you're doing the same...
Okay.
I think I got two of the rules now with this thing.
Which is pretty good.
Very nice.
I actually like this so far.
We can even put something over here that takes a thingy from the side.
Whatever that is.
I mean, it's not very fast rotation here, you know?
Really, what we want to do is to...
Make it spin faster.
And the way to do that...
We could hide the intricacies of the machine up here a little bit.
But you know what?
I like the small pace.
I like when it's like...
Calm.
Let's squash some things.
Can I squash this?
It's even going in.
Oh.
Did I forget how this works?
Maybe it means it doesn't go in.
Here we go!
Oops.
You ready?
Yeah, mill the shit out of this bone!
Oops.
Oh no, keep missing.
Listen to that sound.
Isn't that sweet?
The way it all comes together.
It's wonderful.
And here we go.
We got a...
Bunch of mold meal!
Hey, gimme.
Why can't I pick that up?
Oh!
There's a chance to make white die with that.
That's correct.
That is indeed what's happening.
This inventory is giving me cancer.
Just looking at it...
I feel like I lost four years of my life just looking at it, you know?
I will live less than other people now.
Bone meal.
So this means we can now...
This is what I really want to do.
I need to find a way to automatically plant some seeds to make a tree.
And then we come in with a saw.
And we chop that shit up.
And we collect it all.
We transport it via belt.
And then we completely annihilate it with a very high powered laser.
Pretty much tearing it into small molecules.
And then they all get teleported along the laser.
Quantum style.
Into...
An area...
Far away.
And they get reassembled.
And put on another belt.
And into a little chest.
What do you think?
I...
I gotta say, man.
I love...
Cox.
It's just...
There's something about it, you know?
It's...
Hypnotizing.
Watching them spin.
And do their thing.
Even this thing right here.
That one not...
Maybe not so much.
Oh, no, no, no, no, no, no, no.
We need a bow.
Get away from me.
Hey, asshole.
Why are you just standing...
Get away from my machine, please.
Playsafe.
Good.
Alright.
Let me think.
I think I wanna use this as well.
In a smart way.
Um...
You know what I could do?
Yo.
I have such an idea.
You ready for this?
Watch.
Gonna blow your mind.
It's gonna look insane too!
Let's
extend this shaft.
Boink.
To...
Uh...
Here.
And then we do...
This.
That.
And...
Right.
Then...
Gonna do a bit of...
Oops.
Okay.
Yeah.
Oh, oh.
I know.
We are gonna have to make this...
Like...
That.
Not looking nice though.
Don't like the look of that.
But it's okay.
I'm gonna use a small one.
There.
And...
From here.
Hold on.
I have a point.
It's coming.
Uh...
I lost it.
What was it?
I bring it down...
Into a gearbox.
Actually, wait, wait!
We can go down again!
I see it.
I see it clear now.
It's coming...
Together.
We are gonna have to go ahead and do something drastic.
How does this...
Work?
That...
There we go.
I had it.
Yeah?
This...
No!
Why not?
Oh, okay.
That's why.
Damn it all.
Well, it's not a problem.
We're just gonna do...
Wait, what?
What?
Why doesn't that work?
Why can't I...
Is it because it's touching that?
What?
Oh!
I could use an extension on it.
But extensions are for noobs.
I'm not a noob.
I know what I'm doing.
I'm gonna have to do something...
A little unorthodox.
Fix this one.
Did I just get a genius idea?
Why didn't I just do that?
Actually, that doesn't do anything for me.
That's just a waste of space.
What I could do is this.
Right?
And then this.
And then it still doesn't work.
Because I'm a dumbass.
I can't stop looking at it!
Ah!
It's so nice!
Alright.
Hold on.
I know what to do.
Nevermind.
You didn't see that?
You didn't see that.
I have a plan.
Okay, fine, I'll use your shaft, dammit!
I didn't want to, but I'm gonna.
I'm gonna use it.
Piss!
Wait a second.
I just had an idea.
What if I were to do...
This.
See, now it looks better!
Right?
That's the whole point!
Okay, and then we do a little bit of a...
Little.
Shit!
Wait, that works?
How does that work?
Yeah, that's not gonna fly.
In that case, I would rather we do it like this.
It's held in place like that.
That's cool.
Kinda.
And then we can even go down like this.
But here's the deal.
Wait, why did I...
Oh right, that's why I did that.
Here's the thing though.
Are we... are we...
Is it too much speed?
Maybe we're going too fast now.
Powers of two are dangerous.
Before you know it, you're at infinity.
Maybe I like it that way.
What are you gonna do?
What are you gonna do about it?
I'm gonna rot that like this!
Look at the way the rot goes in.
Are you seeing it?
We're even gonna mask it like this.
It's coming out there!
And it's faster!
And...
You know what?
Check this out!
Here it comes!
Hold on to your hats and goggles, people!
Around like that.
And we're gonna have a little gearbox situation.
I'm gonna box this gear in faster than...
Wait a minute.
Where are the...
Where did I put that?
Aha!
Ewww!
Me no like.
Me like.
Wait, what...
What am I doing actually right now?
I just realized...
Wait, what...
What am I actually doing?
What's the point of all this?
There was a point to this at some point.
Hold on.
Will I bring it in here?
We don't want to do that.
Maybe you like that there.
Let's do a vertical gearbox.
Right in the corner.
That's not gonna work, is it?
Look at those spinny spins.
And then it's gonna come down.
Oh!
Here it is, here it is.
You ready?
Boom.
And now we go even faster.
In fact...
What are we gonna spin on?
Are we gonna spin a mix?
I'm gonna spin a mix.
We don't want the mixing bowl to be in the floor, do we?
Something off about that.
Wait.
This spins that way.
And this is actually not great, is it?
Look how slow this is spinning.
Because wind is kinda slow.
And what I could...
Oh!
Genius incoming.
Why didn't I think of this?
It is obvious.
Vertical gearbox.
Where are you?
Are you back here?
Ah!
There you are.
And this.
Let's put the bet down in this corner now.
So here it comes.
Here it comes.
We're gonna vertical this.
You see the genius?
Hold on, let me think.
I almost see it.
And then we do this.
Look at the way that spins, huh?
That's not bad.
You may ask yourself, why did I just do that?
The answer is simple.
We come down like this now.
But then you may say...
Couldn't you just have done that in a better way?
The answer is yes.
Maybe.
Maybe not.
Maybe I like it this way.
Hold on.
Am I out of range?
What happened to my...
Oh.
Oh, interesting.
Yeah, I can't connect this with a small one at a 90 degree angle.
I keep forgetting.
It's not allowed.
Yo, wait a minute.
No, don't wait, actually.
You can go on without me.
I mean, it's fine.
It's fine.
Not...
Is it fine?
I feel like I don't like this.
What I've done here is very, um...
Not cool.
I like the spinny rod.
I just like looking at this rod spinning.
What do you want?
That's great.
Can I use that somehow?
I'll use that for this thing.
Boom.
Genius acquired.
This was the plan anyway.
Just didn't tell you.
You'll see.
Mechanical press.
This goes here now.
And then we just pull in the rod.
Like that.
I'm gonna use a tiny...
Here.
And then we spin.
Yes!
Dude!
That is frickin' beautiful.
And on the floor?
This one.
So now, whatever I want!
I can just go over here and I can frickin'...
You know.
Squash things.
Let's say I wanna squash some...
Slaps.
Boom.
It's not wanna...
Okay, it doesn't wanna do that.
Also, let me check here.
I'll be good.
512 speed units or...
Stress units, maybe?
SU.
Sine.
I don't know.
Probably stress units.
Stress impact.
I've never seen...
Like...
Are these real units?
I don't think they are.
What did I just do?
Oh!
Wait, you can equip them by right-clicking?
Whoa!
I had no idea you could do that!
That's a crazy feature!
Probably not even part of this mod.
This is like vanilla, I think.
Whoa!
Anyway, I was gonna squash things.
Let me go ahead and do that.
What do I...
Can I squash a diamond?
No.
Don't squash that.
Let's squash some...
Dough!
Knead it for me.
Wait, maybe we should check whether or not it actually squashes.
Do you squash?
What can I squash?
Frick, where's my ingots at?
Are you kidding me?
I have no ingots...
At the ready?
Ah!
Here we go.
Doesn't even work.
It totally works.
Fantastic.
What about...
What can...
Maybe leather?
Nope.
This one I already tried.
String?
I feel like I'm trying the worst things.
Pulp!
Make it even more pulpy.
Yeah!
Wait, what?
Hey!
What the fuck?
That's amazing!
Uh...
Alright!
So, what did I just get?
You said?
Cardboard helmet!
That is funny.
Uh...
Block of cardboard!
W-why?
W- 200% push strength cardboard sword!
Interesting.
Make a book...
Oh!
Interesting.
We can make paper and cardboard and we have a book.
So we don't need leather!
Nice!
What else can I squash?
Squash a...
Amethyst!
No?
We gotta empty this inventory.
Give me this.
Boink!
Not even full.
It's getting worse and worse with the...
Sorting here.
It really is.
It's...
It's not good.
It's not good at all.
Shit.
Maybe some flint.
Squash it for me.
Or...
There's no way we can squash obsidian.
Yeah, it's too strong.
What about lapis lazuli?
No?
Okay.
And a pearl.
Fine.
Sugar cane though.
That's gotta work.
It is so satisfying looking at this thing.
Look at that!
Squash that for me.
And it's also fast!
15 paper...
How much do I get if I just make paper?
3 for 3.
Okay, okay.
But...
Now we take 1.
Oh wait.
Wrong one.
I didn't count.
Hold on.
We have 16 now.
Ah, well...
That's not even better.
Ah, whatever.
What else can I squash?
What would make sense to squash?
Sand?
Nope.
Maybe a nugget.
No, alright.
Probably not blocks, right?
I can also check here.
My squasher is here.
Uh, this is...
Compacting.
This is the squashing.
I can squash dirt!
To make a dirt path.
Uh...
Wait, what?
Why?
Nice, we discovered that now.
Dude, pulp into cardboard?
Is pretty cool!
I do enjoy that.
Let's turn these into...
Uh, sheets.
Got em.
Put em in.
Okay.
Also, I somehow keep, uh...
Let me just turn that off.
Diamonds...
It didn't want to do that, right?
Yeah.
So, speaking of diamonds.
Let's make something out of diamonds.
We have 21, uh...
Enchanting.
Or, I mean, experience.
I want to do enchanting.
Obsidian and a book.
But book is now easy to make, because we have cardboard.
Nice.
Very good.
Alright.
Obsidian we can get with a...
Bucket.
And some lava.
But I don't think there's lava anywhere near here.
No, wait.
I have lava.
I have a bucket of lava.
Somewhere.
There.
The problem is, it's not a lot of lava.
So it's not gonna work.
Yeah.
Unfortunate.
Make another book.
Let me make some new stuff that I haven't made.
Tinted glass.
Make one of those.
Whoa!
Look at that!
Something new.
So what is that?
Altitude sensor!
Alright.
Now we can know our altitude when we're flying.
Altimeter acquired.
Laser sensor!
Oh!
It's gonna sense the output of a laser pointer.
And translate that maybe into...
Maybe this is the receiver.
You know?
That's how you do it.
You don't put a laser on a laser.
Obviously.
Now that I think about it.
This is the one that receives it.
I see.
Make a fireworks rocket.
Uh...
Okay.
Redstone contact.
It's a cardboard chest plate.
Maybe there's a hidden...
effect with this.
Wearable equipment for increased style and stealth!
Sneak to activate an inconspicuous dis...
What?!
Now you have my attention.
Wait a sec.
Squasher!
Show me the ways.
The mixing machine.
Right?
Uh...
Okay.
I can do that.
I'm gonna have it all in here.
This is gonna be the...
Windmill room.
Hand it over.
I will take these now.
Also, if I have this, I can just...
Wasn't there a way to...
Oh, yeah.
Oh, that's nice.
It's kinda weird that they just sort of disappear.
But they go into my inventory.
But it's just...
Odd.
That it works that way.
Okay, so now...
Where are my shafts at?
Somehow I keep losing my items.
They're not in here.
Shaft.
Could I really have used all of them?
Maybe.
Andesite.
Alloys.
Don't even have that on me.
This is what happens when you just deposit...
Oh, there they are.
I found them.
Now it goes like that.
And for the mixer, you wanna have something spinning...
This way.
Right?
So this is...
What is the best way to do that?
Actually, the best way to do that is to go up one and then ahead...
We gotta go on the roof.
This is not pretty, okay?
I get that.
Except from out here.
It's actually kinda pretty from out there.
Right.
And now...
Ah!
But wait.
This is not actually a part that spins.
Maybe this doesn't matter.
I remove this.
And then in between, we have a little vertical gearbox.
It's still being, you know, translated in there.
And then we still have this one there.
And how is that gonna help me?
Now we do this.
Oh, that doesn't s...
Oh, it needs to be vertical.
Crap.
But I can do this.
And...
Not pretty.
Let's just do a simple upwards...
Wait a minute.
Why am I...
No, this is good.
Shaft.
Wheel.
And then we do a big wheel.
Or I just get another...
Hold on a minute.
I could just wheel, wheel, wheel.
But that's not nice, is it?
Or...
Hey, wait, wait, wait.
Even better.
Put the shaft back.
And then put this one back.
And then on this side, we use...
The gearbox.
Now it comes down like that.
So now we have a wheel.
The problem is, it's a little too low now.
That's what I don't like about this.
So can we put it up a little higher?
Dude, this is so weirdly...
Addicting to fiddle with.
You know what I could do?
I could...
Add a wheel...
Like this...
Here.
Ah, but then slower of course.
Unless I...
Use a small one.
There.
And then here.
No, this is...
Ah, I don't like it.
I think I'm trying to do too much with too little here.
Here's another idea.
What if we just take the original source of the power?
Meaning the windmill.
And...
So this one's spinning, right?
What if I slap a wheel on that?
Not like that though.
But like this.
So now that's spinning.
And we like when it's spinning.
The problem is, this needs to be a big wheel.
What do I think about it?
Yeah, I actually like that.
And then...
We're gonna apply a little wheel...
Here.
But now we have to work with, um...
Making this...
Compliant again.
And that's also not...
Something you wanna do.
I don't know what I'm...
Talking about here.
I'm losing my mind.
Big wheel on top.
Do we really have to make it fast?
Okay, hold on.
We already got all this power, right?
We use the area of the roof...
To our advantage.
Like this.
And then we do...
This.
This is getting so weird.
I don't know.
It doesn't even fit there.
Crap.
That's why you need the extra...
Uh...
Spoke.
But that...
That's not good either, is it?
That doesn't quite work.
Shit, man!
Why is it so difficult?
What's wrong with this?
Do we put a...
Oh.
This one?
And then we simply display it proudly?
This is turning into some bullshit.
What the fuck am I doing?
Stop!
Stop everything.
Put a big wheel on that.
That's more like it.
And then we do this.
This.
It's decently fast now.
Yeah!
Why not?
And then here...
Now we...
Now we fast as fuck, boy.
We bring the rod down.
And then...
We do this.
And this.
And down.
This room is now also the windmill room.
In fact, the whole house is the windmill room.
And then instead of that, we bring in that!
And there it is, baby.
There it is.
We made it.
Isn't that just a thing of beauty?
Oh dear lord.
This is not great.
Let's just say that.
But hey!
If it works, but looks stupid, it ain't stupid.
There we go.
That's a bullshit saying, by the way.
I don't think that's true.
Where's all my stone at, though?
I think some of it disappeared.
Yeah, see, now the problem is, we don't have enough stone, so...
We are gonna implement a little bit of a skylight here.
Also, that way we can see the gears up top.
Huh?
Not bad.
High-tech house!
Let's actually go to bed.
Running out of sleeping space.
Okay, so...
Let me get this out of the way.
I know this is a disaster, okay?
I fully am aware...
Of how absolutely terrible this entire thing is.
I know.
But dude, I'm having such a blast just messing with this.
You know?
This is great.
I mean, look at this!
I can't stop looking at it.
Yeah, this is some real bullshit, what I've done here.
I really should have just taken this speed right here and used it.
In some smart way.
But alas!
I'm actually gonna...
Make this a little more pretty.
Check this out.
See, that's pretty right there.
But not into the glass.
We don't like that.
Wait, what the...
This could easily have been done in a better way.
Just by looking at this.
But, uh...
For example...
Just moving this over here.
Except, would that not have put it here?
Ah, probably.
But I like it.
I like it.
What else should I be doing here with this?
I think it could look cool if I had these blocks...
Right on this edge here.
Let's see how it looks.
Just with two of them.
Hmm...
By the way!
Let me see something here.
What did that say again?
Brass...
Or...
Anticide casing can be used to decorate shafts.
Brass.
You say.
Wait, brass?
We've read about that.
What about gold?
Is that a thing?
Does anything work?
Do I have to use this?
I think I...
I turned all my gold bars into sheets, unfortunately.
Yeah.
Yeah, that's ugly, man!
Fuck!
I hate what I've done!
I like the look with the windmill.
But now it's ruined.
Look at this ugly-ass rod over there.
It's spinning.
It's mesmerizing, but it's not...
It's not good.
I...
I'm a big hater.
Yeah, this...
We can't do that.
Also...
If I make these sails bigger...
More power?
More wind?
Bigger...
Area, right?
Surface area matters.
I don't think I have any sails left, though.
I need more, um...
Whatchamacallit.
Silk.
No.
Wool?
What is it called?
Sheep's...
Clothing.
Sheep shears...
At the seashore.
Hmm...
There's a word...
Is it wool?
Is it...
Hey!
What?!
That's new.
Since when have you been able to make wool out of string?
Exquisite me?
What the...
This is some next level shit.
Uh...
With one wool block...
How many sails?
Two.
That's not gonna cut it.
Yeah, we gotta start breeding some sheep.
We gotta have a backyard of that.
This right here, I just...
It looks like a duck every time I open the door and go out here.
This is the beak.
This is its neck.
And it's just out there...
Messing with me in the distance.
You see it, right?
And then we have this bullshit over...
What is this place?
Maybe I will...
Change location entirely and forget I ever did this.
We will never...
Talk of this again.
Whatever happened on these planes...
Shall stay on these planes.
There's a gang over there who's raiding the countryside.
Good thing they're not coming over here.
Yeah.
I'm gonna relocate, guys.
But next time.
I...
Am too tired to think.
It's going a little overboard.
It is.
Let me put on some music.
Some westwardly winds.
Oh my god.
I nearly drank the whole bottle.
Whoops.
How y'all doing?
What did you think of the mod?
Dude, create is kind of cool, huh?
How many of you have not played this mod?
Wow.
Thank you, Ducks King of Let...
Wait, Ducks Knight of Lettuce.
You make me think of that quote from...
Succession.
Something about lettuce.
King of Spinach.
His Majesty or something.
I forget the exact quote, but yeah.
Thank you very much, man.
Thank you to everyone who's been subscribing.
I see there's a lot in the list.
Thank you so much.
I hope you had a good time.
I had a fantastic time.
There's over a thousand people in here watching this.
At this hour.
That blows my mind.
Like, I was pretty much out there just sailing in my mind.
For the past three hours or so.
Like, I don't even remember what I did the last three hours.
Yes, I do.
I made the windmill.
But I honestly couldn't tell you how long I spent on that windmill.
I think the first stream of Create has got to be the hardest.
Because it's just incredibly overwhelming with all the stuff I got bombarded with.
Even though the progression mod, you know, kinda tried to keep it in check a little bit.
Like, can you imagine if I got dropped into this with like a recipe book containing everything?
It would have been impossible.
I need to be on some kind of drug, I think, to actually manage that.
I'm too scatterbrained for that.
It was great seeing you get so excited with each new ponder.
I think the ponder system is unbelievably beautiful.
And whoever coded that deserves all the praise in the world.
Because that is just pure genius.
It is elegant, it is smooth, it is aesthetically pleasing.
I can't praise it enough.
What an amazing idea for a system.
And I cannot believe this is a mod.
There's more love poured into this than many games I've played.
Is the blue book mod the Frank mod?
It is.
Frank took care of this one.
Frank included a lot of unit tests.
And a lot of self-testing.
Because obviously it had to be done with as little involvement from my side as possible.
Obviously I had to check some things.
Make sure they worked.
Very basic things.
But most of it was tested by Frank.
Yes.
What do you think about bananas?
I...
Honestly pretty mid.
As a raw fruit.
Like just eating them like that.
Unless they're like perfectly ripe then it's okay.
But if you put them in a banana split.
Then they are S tier.
Completely elevated.
Or if you make banana bread.
S plus tier.
Best thing ever.
Or banana pancakes.
Yeah.
Is it gonna be public?
Yeah for sure.
I just wanna iron out a couple bucks.
I saw a couple of bucks today.
Something that for sure shouldn't be like it was.
You need to try fried banana.
Wait fried banana?
You mean like in a deep fryer?
Really?
That sounds weird.
Weird.
But also kinda...
Interesting.
Why do you enjoy cocks touching each other so much?
By the way, am I saying cocks weird?
Am I saying it wrong?
I know that it sounds close to cocks.
Am I...
I mean they sound very similar.
How am I saying it wrong?
You sound normal saying it?
Okay.
Is the accent...
No, I...
Listen.
Listen to the difference.
Cocks.
And cocks.
I love cocks.
I must have said that at some point.
But I...
Obviously I try to emphasize cog.
You know?
And not cock.
Yeah, it does sound the same.
I hate that it sounds the same.
It's so annoying.
You said I love cocks.
It's so hypnotizing watching them spin.
I'm just imagining like a field.
Of cocks.
And they're all like spinning.
In that field.
It's just hilarious.
Oh no.
Try saying cocks to be clear.
Okay, I can say...
Hmm.
Uh...
I can say...
What about a...
Spanish way of saying cog?
There must be a Spanish word for it.
I love saying Spanish words.
We can replace it with a Spanish word.
No, it's not gears.
What is it in Spanish?
Cogola?
See, that kinda sounds like cock still.
That's not gonna...
That's not gonna work.
Wind turbine field?
Yeah.
Let's just call them gears.
Genius, actually.
Wow.
Sometimes the simple solution...
Is just there and you don't notice it.
Something about trees in the forest.
We call them tooth wheels.
So do we in Denmark.
Tenjul.
Yeah.
Zanrad.
Not to be confused with Farrad.
We call them G's bro.
Gears of War.
I've never played Gears of War.
I will not play Jenny Mod.
Officially.
But I will play it on my...
OnlyFans.
That is coming.
I'm not.
Isn't that mod like illegal?
Yeah man, the authorities are like, you can't do that.
You can't do that.
You can't watch that.
It's illegal.
Don't play that.
You're gonna get arrested.
How much will the OnlyFans cost?
Hmm.
I don't know what people charge nowadays.
I have never subscribed to an OnlyFans, so I don't know what the going rate is normally.
But I have heard that...
You can earn a lot of money there.
Will Stuart be on it?
Nah.
I don't think he's into that.
Why it took so long with slabs?
Dude, right?
Freakin' slabs were the solution of all things.
To get the damn windmill...
Uh...
Bearing.
I cannot believe that.
Of all the blocks in the game.
It's like my most hated one.
We had slap sanity for half the stream.
Oh, did you?
Wait, I...
Let's do a quick vote, actually.
I need to see...
Or a poll.
I'm gonna make a poll here.
Have you played...
Create?
Yes or no?
Is this the first time you're seeing this?
Mod.
I'm assuming most of you have played Minecraft.
Like 99% have played Minecraft.
Oh, actually there's a bunch of you who haven't seen the mod.
Let me ask you then, to the people that have not played this.
What did you think of it?
From watching this?
From your perspective, who's never played it?
What did you think?
Did it look cool?
Not a fan?
Amazing.
Looks interesting.
Overwhelming?
Yeah, overwhelming for sure.
And...
Apparently, we've just scratched the surface of it too.
Like, I've pretty much just been messing about with gears.
Super cool, I might get it now.
Cool.
Very cool, but yeah, overwhelming.
Yeah.
I think we should slow down next stream and actually focus on setting up more of the basics.
Which I wanted to do today, but then I kept getting distracted.
You know, I wanted to spend today making a house and a field.
And getting some cows.
And just get that going, right?
But then I kept unlocking things.
And I just could not help myself.
But at least I got that out of my system now.
So next time I can calm down a bit more.
Focus on a lot of the essentials.
And then...
get into some of the more advanced stuff.
Are you gonna settle in this spot or travel somewhere else?
I will either...
take care of crimes...
or I will travel somewhere else.
So the answer is...
depends on whether or not I wanna take care of the crimes.
And whether or not I wanna be met with the sight of that...
unholy creation that is now...
in front of me when I log in again.
What's the goal for this season?
I guess to...
just have fun.
There's really not any specific goal.
I just wanna play Minecraft again.
I wanna make cool houses.
do some of the stuff I maybe never did in the second season.
Some of the dreams I had.
And then...
with the addition of this mod now...
create extra things on top of that.
Make it more exciting.
Spice it up a bit, you know?
Rotating bookcase!
Yes!
Finally!
I will rotate my bookcases.
It is actually a thing now.
Yeah, maybe there's a machine I can make to take care of the crimes.
That's true.
If there's a question to be asked...
whether or not I can now do something I couldn't before...
most likely the answer is yes.
Not even as a secret door.
Just rotating because.
Because it's cool, yeah.
Exactly.
The rotating bookcase plotline took three seasons.
To be fair though, I never really...
tried...
to make it, you know?
Like, I did shortly, but then I quickly realized...
oh, this is gonna be a tough one.
And then I kinda gave up on it.
Like, it was actually...
just breaking my brain how you would do it in...
in vanilla.
I assume you still can, but it's gonna be...
really complicated.
How many mods are in the modpack?
Only two.
No, three technically, I guess.
There's Create.
Aeronautics.
Which is, I guess, just an add-on to...
Create.
And then I have some performance mods.
Like Sodium, Lithium...
and Ferrite Core.
And then I have the...
what's it called?
Create Progression mod.
The one that I cooked up with Frank.
No Gym mod?
Yeah, I forgot it!
I wanted to include it.
I forgot it.
Pure and simple.
It was supposed to be in.
But then again...
I never used a button today.
So it doesn't really matter, does it?
Maybe it was in.
And you just didn't know.
I was lying.
The mod was in.
I just didn't...
create a button.
Did you know Aeronautics was made by a Swede?
No.
But now I'm gonna tear down my windmill.
And I will not be flying.
I'll stick to the ground.
Thank you.
Just enough item...
Gym.
Ah, you messed it up there.
By the way...
Just enough items...
in this...
style of the mod...
is finally living up to the name of it.
Right?
If you don't do anything to it...
it's not just enough items.
It's way too many items.
Now it's just enough!
What's with that name though?
It should be TMI.
You can get bundles if you enable them in experimental features.
Maybe I'll do that.
We'll see.
I just need to get my act together and fix my inventory.
Most of my inventory today was because I was messing around with the new funny things.
And I just...
couldn't wait, you know?
So I put the sorting aside...
and...
jumped right into...
trying all kinds of crazy things.
TMI was OG.
Wait, was it actually called?
TMI once?
I totally just made that up.
That's the whole joke.
Too many items is the OG mod that existed before creative mode.
So you can get...
Oh!
Shit!
I didn't even know that!
That's funny!
Oh!
I totally just pulled that out of my ass.
That's funny.
What machine idea hypes you up the most?
Honestly, man?
That...
I just wanna...
have a homestead.
You know, with a windmill on my house.
That crushes my wheat.
Presses my grapes.
And then I want...
an automated...
tractor out in the field.
Just like the ones they have in Interstellar, you know?
They drive around and they collect the wheat.
And I grab that wheat.
And I put it inside the press.
And I mix it up.
And I make dough.
I cut it into tiny pieces after baking it.
And I put it...
Or I put some butter on it with some...
garlic.
And I sip some wine.
Pressed by the grapes from the presser.
That's... that's what I want, man.
And...
Make it sound so lewd.
No, I...
It's more like...
Maybe I'm kind of...
Maybe my dream in real life is leaking a little bit, you know?
I think, uh...
It's better as a dream, though, in real life.
Because in real life...
With a farm...
There's actually work involved.
Work that I probably wouldn't like doing.
But that's why you have the machines doing it for you.
Maybe there's like...
I don't know...
Like a Tesla robot in the future.
Like 50 years from now.
Who's just walking around in my fields...
Collecting wheat.
You know?
And it's...
Coming back with it in the evening.
And they're pouring my wine or something.
I don't fucking know.
Maybe it'll happen at some point, you know?
We're gonna get robots just working for us.
Yeah, Stardew Valley...
I will definitely play that.
Yeah, I'm gonna take notes.
I already thought about it as soon as I made the book.
And I saw the little, uh...
Book with the quill on it.
I considered it in the moment.
But yeah, next time for sure I'll make a book.
We're gonna have a proper...
Oh man, I actually have so many ideas.
The thing is though, the ideas need to be...
What do you call it?
Like right now I have ideas, but they're grounded in my vanilla brain.
You know what I mean?
So as soon as I get more comfortable with create...
In this world...
I think my ideas will sort of, um...
Change and...
Morph a little bit.
So I don't wanna build too much...
To only tear it down later.
Because I discovered some really cool thing.
That can do things differently.
That's why I'm talking about this simple setup.
Simple but elegant.
You know, farmstead.
You really need to add Farmers Delight mod?
I'll take a look at it.
I'm not gonna promise anything.
I do wanna keep it simple.
Because if I add another mod, it's gonna open the floodgates for more mods.
And I really don't want that.
Maybe I'll just keep it completely...
As it is.
And not change anything.
But I promise I'll give it a quick look.
Yes.
I'll check it out.
Are you gonna add energy generated by chat counter?
Oh, that's right!
Good- Thank you for reminding me of that.
I would have totally forgotten if you hadn't said that.
Yeah.
It's a great idea.
I'll see what I can do.
About that.
It shouldn't be too hard to make.
I already have the mechanism wired in for...
For every single time someone posts a chat message.
I can easily make that fill up something, you know?
Based on how fast you guys are typing.
But yeah.
Oh, I forgot that the wheels were spinning all this time.
I'm just looking at Twitch, right?
I'm not looking at the wheels spinning.
I saw some people saying that it was lagging.
No, the wheels are spinning whenever you type something.
Whenever someone types, it...
It spins the wheels.
But maybe I can somehow make it so that...
If you guys type at a reasonable speed...
It'll switch over to just a single animation that plays, you know?
So it's more smooth.
Everyone's saying spin.
I mean, I had to do the cocks, right?
I made gears for this mod.
What you're seeing on the waiting screen right now is actually...
An accurate representation of my current house in Create.
Seen from the...
From the top.
That's what it looks like.
There's no rhyme or reason to it.
Okay.
It's time for me to go to bed, actually.
Thank you so much for watching, guys.
And thank you so much for all the subscriptions and...
Just for hanging out and checking this out with me.
Minecraft is back, baby.
This is gonna be a special one, I think.
I'll see you around.
Bye-bye.
I'll have my new biop of my own spark.
This is covid 229.
We are now a safety truck for an crisis JOHNSTESS إDAL produce for Easter Reminds.
ersten Frank Alexander Ke Sunstone Вы ten years later in the Redemption that has been rejected.
If I have something new here, I think you'll see you tomorrow.
Before that, we'll see you tomorrow, we'll be over many of yours.